2306, please.
麻烦你 2306
Hello, honey. How you doing?
甜心 你好吗?
Good. What did he say?
好 他怎么说?
Uh-huh. Is he still there? How long ago did he leave?
他还在那里吗? 他离开多久了?
Uh-huh. I'm stopping here, then I got a little meeting,
我一会儿还要开个会
and then I'll... I would if I could.
然后...可以的话我会去看你
As soon as I can. Let me get off and I...
我尽快好了 我要动身了...
let me get off and I prom... I promise you it'll be okay.
我答应你一切都会办好的
A bunch of bullshit. Waste a good man's time.
一堆废话 浪费我的时间
Hi, could I speak to Dr. Lowenstein, please?
你好 卢云医生在吗?
It's rather important. Could you get him for me?
我有很重要的事找他 请他听电话好吗?
Bunch of bullshit trying to make a living on these deadbeat leads.
和那些二溜子谈生意真费劲
I swear to God, Shel, I'm on a sit today...
我今天开了个会...
Hello, Mrs. Swoboda, this is Dave Moss.
你好 史太太 我是大卫莫斯
Yeah, we spoke yesterday.
对 我们昨天通过电话
Now on the Rio Rancho Estates, we've had a situation just come up.
现在 关于尼奥牧场的事 我们遇上个新情况
The president of our company is in town just one day,
我们公司的主席只能在镇上待一天
- and he has certain parcels... - Doctor...
- 他有单生意要和你们... - 医生...
well, could you get... what do you mean?
你能让史先生... 你什么意思?
He's not there? I have to speak to him.
他不在? 我有话要跟他说
Yes, it is fairly urgent. Mr. Levene.
很重要的事情 我是赖芬先生
No, I can't be reached. I'll get back to him.
我没固定联络方式 我会再打电话找他的
He has certain parcels... certain choice parcels
他有项投资计划
which he's given me a hold on for the next 48 hours.
他只给我48小时时间
What would be the best time to get you and your husband together?
什么时候最好? 我是说来见你和你先生
Say, tonight, at 10:00, or tomorrow at 8:00?
今晚十点还是明早八点?
Okay.
好
Okay, what would be the best time to do that?
那什么时候最好?
Look, you sent in the... no, no, listen to me now...
听着 你寄来了... 不 不 先听我说
I've got 48 hours to make you a lot of money.
我现在有四十八小时来让你发财
Well, when will he be home? Fine, I'll call you back in 10 minutes.
他什么时候回家? 好 我十分钟后再打来吧
They don't give you the leads, they don't give you the support,
他们不给你指引 不给你支持
- they don't give you dick. - Yeah.
- 他们什么都不给你 - 没错
Then they're yanking us in on some sales conference.
然后就使劲拉我们进什么销售会
When's the last time anybody learned a goddamn thing?
上次有人赚到钱是什么时候的事了?
All it does is some jerk shoots his mouth off.
真想找人开枪射死他
I swear to God, Shel, I got half a mind to go across the street.
我发誓 我几乎想要跳槽了
I got half a mind to go with you if they'd take me.
如果他们要我的话 我也跟你一起跳槽
You never know... I was talking to Jerry Graff last week.
你永远不会知道 我上星期和谢利格拉夫见过面
I got to call these deadbeats back.
我得给那些二溜子打电话了
I can't make a goddamn dollar with these leads,
那些狗屁生意不能让我赚到一毛钱
and you're killing my ass on the street.
而你却要把我踢到街上自生自灭
- I'm sorry you aren't happy here. - That's cute,
- 我真难过你在这里做的不开心 - 别假惺惺了
but you're running this office like a bunch of bullshit.
你把这办公室弄的一团糟
You're on an override... you make money, we make money.
你赚到钱公司才能赚钱
- I'd like you to make more money. - Then don't go waste my time.
- 所以我希望你多赚点钱 - 那就别浪费我的时间
- A sales conference? - The strategy comes from downtown.
- 给我更多生意 而不是开销售会议 - 策略是商业区的人定下来的
Oh, the strategy? The strategy?
策略?
- Well, I think I'll pass. - I wouldn't.
- 我想我还是放弃好了 - 我不会
- Why is that? - When you come, then you'll see.
- 为什么? - 你是我的话便会明白的
- Shelly. - John.
- 沙利 - 约翰
Are you ready to do or die tonight?
你今晚打算干活吗?
Oh yeah, always ready, John.
我随时准备好候命 约翰
Always ready, John. Now, one thing...
随时 约翰 对了...
we were talking about the leads. We got some new ones?
我们在说那些生意 又有新的生意了吗?
That's what we're going to talk about at the meeting.
我们会在会上讨论这个的
We are? Because I'm running into a bit of a snag.
我在工作上遇到些阻碍
Yes, I've seen your sales figures.
对 我看过你的销售数字了
That's the leads. You give me a better lead...
你给我更好的生意...
That's what we're going to be talking about.
那正是我们要谈的
I'm in a bind... personal problems.
这是私人麻烦
- I could use a leg up. - After the meeting.
- 我完全同意 - 会后再谈吧
- I hear the new Glengarry leads... - After the meeting, Shel.
- 我听说格兰加利那边的生意... - 开完会再谈 沙利
- Hey, Ricky. - Hello, John.
- 嘿 理查德 - 你好 约翰
- Wet out there tonight. - Huh?
- 外面在下雨 - 什么?
- Wet out there tonight. - Uh-huh.
- 外面在下雨 - 哦
- Maybe it'll break the heat. - Yeah.
- 也许这有助减低热度 - 对
Al, give me a quick J&B, huh? Double.
艾尔 给我一杯J＆B 两杯
Cutty, Al.
好一个坏女人 艾尔
- They say... - Huh?
- 他们说... - 什么?
they say it was so hot downtown this afternoon,
他们说下午商业区那里非常热
grown men on the street corner were going up to cops
热得街角的人走向警察
begging the cops to shoot them.
求警察开枪杀了他们
They say you should not drink alcohol when it's so hot.
据说天热的时候不应该喝酒
- Who says that? - Something I read.
- 谁说的? - 我从报上看到的
For they say it dehydrates you.
他们说这会让你脱水
They say you should drink water,
他们还说你应该喝清水
but I subscribe to the law of contrary public opinion.
但我却比较相信这样一个哲理
If everyone thinks one thing, then I say bet the other way.
当大家看法都一样的时候 我便会持相反的看法
Added to which, you know they're wrong.
那是因为你知道他们是错的
That's what I'm saying.
我就是那个意思
- Slow tonight. - Oh, yeah.
- 今晚走慢点 - 嗯
Well, I guess everybody's staying home.
我想大家都应是留在家里
If my daughter calls, anybody calls,
如果我女儿或别的人打电话来
I'm over at the office. Thanks.
就说我在办公室 谢谢
I had a woman in White Plains on the hook...
我找到个穿着朴素的女人
five units, Mountain View... what happens?
她有五个单位 能看见山景的那种 发生什么事了?
She has to check with her lawyer.
她要找她的律师咨询一下
- You let her check with her lawyer? - What could I do?
- 你让她找她的律师了? - 我还能怎么做?
- I dunno. - Shelly.
- 我不知道 - 沙利
- Huh? - Who's the guy?
- 什么事? - 那人是谁?
Couldn't tell you.
不能告诉你
I don't like the whole thing, because all I need is a lead.
我不喜欢那样 我只是需要一单生意
- They won't give out... - Uh-huh.
- 他们却不给我... - 哦
The rich get richer, that's the law of the land.
富者越富是这国家的法则
Who belongs to the BM...?
那宝马是谁的?
It is 7:30.
已经七点半了
So who is that?
那他究竟是谁?
And where is Mr. Roma?
还有诺马在哪里?
Well, I'm not a leash, so I don't know, do I?
我怎么会知道
Let me have your attention for a moment.
大家都仔细听好了
You're talking about what? You're talking about...
你们在谈些什么? 你们在谈...
bitching about that sale you shot,
你们找到的那单生意
some son of a bitch don't want to buy land,
有些人不想买土地
somebody don't want what you're selling,
有些人不要你在卖的东西
some broad you're trying to screw, so forth.
某个你们想榨出油水的吝啬鬼
Let's talk about something important.
还是谈些更重要的事情吧
- Are they all here? - All but one.
- 都到齐了吗? - 还差一个
I'm going anyway.
不管他了 开会
Let's talk about something important.
还是谈些更重要的事情吧
Put that coffee down.
放下手上的咖啡
Coffee's for closers only.
咖啡是给成功人士喝的
You think I'm fucking with you?
你以为我是在闹着玩的吗?
I am not fucking with you.
我不是和你开玩笑
I'm here from downtown.
我是从商业区来的
I'm here from Mitch and Murray.
我是从默里公司来的
And I'm here on a mission of mercy.
我是来指引你们的
- Your name's Levene? - Yeah.
- 你是赖芬? - 对
You call yourself a salesman, you son of a bitch?
你个狗娘养的人称自己做经纪人?
I don't got to listen to this shit.
我不想再听下去了
You certainly don't, 'cause the good news is, you're fired.
你当然不会再听下去了 因为有好消息等着你 你被开除了
The bad news is you've got... all of you've got...
坏消息是你们大家有...
just one week to regain your jobs,
一星期时间保住你们的饭碗
starting with tonight... starting with tonight's sit.
从今晚这会议开始算起
Oh, have I got your attention now?
你们都听清楚了吗?
Good...
很好
'cause we're adding a little something
因为我们还给这个月的销售竞争
to this month's sales contest.
加了点东西
As you all know, first prize is a Cadillac Eldorado.
你们都知道第一名的奖励 是一辆卡迪拉克
Anybody want to see second prize?
有人想知道第二名的奖励是什么吗?
Second prize is a set of steak knives.
是一套牛扒刀具
Third prize is you're fired.
三奖是炒鱿鱼
Do you get the picture? Are you laughing now?
明白了吗? 你们还在笑吗?
You got leads. Mitch and Murray paid good money.
你做成生意 公司会付很好的价钱
Get their names to sell them.
努力做成每一单生意
You can't close the leads you're given,
你不能拒绝做交代下来的生意
you can't close shit, you are shit!
你是堆臭狗屎!
Hit the bricks, pal, and beat it, 'cause you are going out!
不管多困难都要做成生意!
- The leads are weak. - The leads are weak?
- 给我们的生意都很棘手 - 棘手?
The fucking leads are weak? You're weak.
他妈的生意很棘手? 其实是你太烂
I've been in this business 15 years.
我干这行已经十五年了
- What's your name? - Fuck you...
- 你叫什么名字? - 操你...
that's my name! You know why, mister?
那就是我的名字! 你知道为什么吗?
Because you drove a Hyundai to get here tonight,
因为你今晚开现代的烂车来开会
I drove an $80,000 BMW. That's my name.
我开的是八万美元的宝马 那就是我的名字
And your name is "You're wanting."
而你的名字是"不够格"
You can't play in the man's game? You can't close them?
你没资格玩这游戏
Then go home and tell your wife your troubles.
那就回家向你老婆诉苦
Because only one thing counts in this life...
因为生活中只有一件事最重要
get them to sign on the line which is dotted!
就是让客户在合约上签字!
You hear me, you fucking faggots?
听到了吗 你们这群混蛋?
"A-B-C"
A... Always, B... Be, C... Closing.
A...永远 B...做 C...成功者
Always Be Closing.
永远做个成功者
"Always Be Closing."
"永远做个成功者"
A-I-D-A
"A-I-D-A."
"Attention, Interest, Decision, Action."
"注意 兴趣 决定 行动"
Attention... Do I have your attention?
注意... 大家注意听我说两句好吗?
Interest... Are you interested?
兴趣...你感兴趣吗?
I know you are, because it's fuck or walk.
我知道你感兴趣 因为别无选择
You close or you hit the bricks.
不想失败的话就打破障碍
Decision... Have you made your decision for Christ?
决定...你有做出决定吗?
And Action. "A-I-D-A."
还有...行动 "A-I-D-A"
Get out there... you got the prospects coming in.
走出这里...你们还有大好前程
You think they came in to get out of the rain?
你以为他们进来是为了躲雨?
A guy don't walk on the lot lest he wants to buy.
一个人不是要买便不会走进来
They're sitting out there waiting to give you their money.
他们正等着送钱给你
Are you gonna take it?
你有本事拿吗?
Are you man enough to take it?
你够胆去拿吗?
Crap.
废话
What's the problem, pal? You... Moss.
有什么问题吗 伙计? 你 莫斯
You're such a hero, you're so rich,
你是如此的英雄 如此的富有
how come you're here wasting your time with a bunch of bums?
为何你会来这里跟一群酒鬼浪费时间?
You see this watch?
看见这表了吗?
- You see this watch? - Yeah.
- 看见了吗? - 看到了
That watch costs more than your car.
这表比你的车还要贵
I made $9 70,000 last year. How much you make?
去年我赚了97万 你赚了多少?
You see, pal... that's who I am, and you're nothing.
伙计 那就是我 而你就是个无名小子
Nice guy? I don't give a shit.
我从不做好人
Good father? Fuck you... go home and play with your kids.
好父亲?去你妈的 回家陪孩子去玩吧
You want to work here... close!
你们要想继续在这里工作... 那就围着客户转!
You think this is abuse?
你认为这是侮辱?
You think this is abuse, you cocksucker?
你们这群混蛋认为这是侮辱?
You can't take this, how can you take the abuse you get on a sit?
连这都受不了的话 怎样面对谈生意时的尴尬场面?
You don't like it, leave.
你不喜欢的话就离开好了
I can go out there tonight... the materials you got...
我可以用你们手上的资料
make myself $15,000. Tonight... in two hours!
为自己赚到一万五千块 今晚 两小时内!
Can you?
你可以吗?
Go and do likewise. "A-I-D-A."
照我说的去做 "A-I-D-A"
Get mad, you son of a bitches. Get mad!
疯狂的去推销 狗娘养的!
You know what it takes to sell real estate?
你知道卖房地产的技巧吗?
It takes brass balls to sell real estate.
这可不是件容易的事情
Go and do likewise, gents.
照我说的去试试吧
The money's out there... you pick it up, it's yours,
钱就在外面 只要你拿的走 就是你的了
you don't, I got no sympathy for you.
你拿不到的话我也不会同情你
You want to go out on those sits tonight and close...
今晚就去谈生意 围着客户转
close... it's yours.
那钱就是你的了
Not, you're gonna be shining my shoes.
不然你就只能替我擦鞋子
And you know what you'll be saying.
你知道那有多少可怜
Bunch of losers sitting around in a bar,
一群失败者坐在酒吧里
"Oh yeah, I used to be a salesman. It's a tough racket."
"我以前是个经纪 过着花天酒地的生活"
These are the new leads.
这些是新的生意
These are the Glengarry leads.
格兰加利的生意
And to you, they're gold. And you don't get them.
对你们来说 这些就是金子 你们得不到这些生意
Why?
为什么呢?
Because to give them to you is just throwing them away.
因为把这些生意交给你们 就等于把它们扔掉
They're for closers.
这些只能给有能力的人去做
I'd wish you good luck,
我祝你们好运
but you wouldn't know what to do with it if you got it.
但你们即使得到这些生意 也不知道该如何处理
And to answer your question, pal... "Why am I here?"
现在我来回答你的问题 "为什么我来这里?"
I came here because Mitch and Murray asked me to.
我来这里是因为公司要我来
They asked me for a favor. I said, "The real favor...
他们要我帮忙 我说 真要我帮忙的话就是...
follow my advice and fire your fucking ass,
听我的劝告 炒掉那些废物
because a loser is a loser."
因为失败者永远是失败者
Bunch of fucking nonsense...
废话连篇
treat people like that.
竟然那样对待我们
The fuck is he going to get off?
他要走了?
- Mickey Mouse sales conference. - He didn't mean it.
- 老鼠会 - 他不是这个意思
I'm sure he didn't mean it about trimming down the sales quota.
我肯定他不是要降低生意配额
Where is Roma? Where the hell is Mr. Ricky Roma?
理查德诺马在哪里?
All the while we got to sit here, eat this nonsense?
我们在这听废话的时候他在哪里?
Hello? Mr. Levene. How's she doing?
我是赖芬 她还好吗?
Uh-huh, yeah. Is she awake?
她醒了吗?
Oh, the doctor came by. What did he say?
医生来过了 他说了什么没有?
Uh-huh. I can't come in tonight.
我今晚不能来了
I think... I know she is. I know that she is.
我知道她想见我
I've gotta go out. Will you please tell her when she wakes?
我现在要出去了 她醒了以后请转告她
I've got to go out. Tell her I'll call her from the road.
我得出去了 告诉她我会在路上打电话给她的
Thank you.
谢谢
Gentlemen, you heard the man.
先生们 你们都听到了
What is this in aid of?
这对我们有什么帮助?
- As of tonight... - What is this? Excuse me.
- 今晚... - 对不起
What it's in aid of is that Mitch and Murray...
总公司要我们...
Fuck Mitch and Murray! I'm doing my job,
去他妈的破公司! 我是在工作
I got to put up with this childishness?
不是在陪这小儿科的家伙玩!
I don't make the rules. I'm paid to run the office.
规矩不是我定的 我负责这办公室的运作
You don't like the rules, Dave? There's the door!
你不喜欢这些规矩 戴夫? 门就在那儿!
Two lead cards for tonight, two lead cards for tomorrow.
今天晚上两单生意 明天还有两单
As you heard, end of the month,
你们都听到了 到了月底
top salesman on the board gets the Eldorado.
营业额最高的经纪就得到那辆卡迪拉克
- Next man down the... - What about the good leads?
- 第二名... - 那些好生意呢?
- The leads I've given you. - But these leads are shit.
- 我给了你们生意了 - 可你给我们的都是垃圾!
They're old... I've seen that name 100 times.
我见过这名字一百次了
- The leads are assigned randomly. - What about the new leads?
- 生意是随机分配的 - 新的生意呢?
The new leads... the Glengarry leads.
新的生意...格兰加利的生意
I've got them. I'm going to hang onto them.
暂时不会分配给你们
And they'll be assigned to closers,
我打算交给有能力的人去做
based on the sales volume, first to Roma.
看销量的话 首先应该交给诺马
- Where is Roma? - Don't worry about Roma.
- 他在哪里? - 别担心诺马
He'll get his leads, you've got yours.
诺马会有他的生意 你也是
He's top name on the board, so he don't have to be here?
他的营业额最高 所以就不用来开这会?
That's correct! And as the hour is waning,
没错! 时间一分一秒的过去
I suggest you... those of you who are interested
我建议对这工作还感兴趣的人
in a continuing job with this organization, get to work.
赶紧去工作吧
That's garbage. Bullshit.
废话
- Thank you for your attention. - Bullshit!
- 多谢 - 废话!
How am I supposed to close these? Look at this.
我有什么办法卖掉这些? 看看这个
I've had this guy before. I've been to his house twice.
我以前和这家伙打过交道 我去过他的屋子两次
I... I can't... I can't close this stuff.
我做不了这单生意
Shelly, how am I supposed to...
沙利 我怎么可能...
They're going to bounce me out of a job.
他们会开除我的!
Hello, Mr. Palermo? I'm sorry.
是巴勒莫先生吗? 我很抱歉
Mr. Speice? Mr. Robert Speice?
史先生?史罗拔先生?
Yeah, this is George Aaronow.
对 我是艾乔治
I'm with Rio. I spoke with your wife earlier.
我早前跟你太太通过电话了 关于尼奥牧场的事情
I'm the vice president of Rio Rancho Properties in Furman, Arizona.
我是亚利桑拿地产公司副主席
Yes. I'm calling from the airport, and consulting my map,
我是从机场打来的 正在看地图
I see that you and your wife live near the airport.
我发现你们就住在机场附近
I have some rather... rather unusual,
我有一些很不寻常的
rather good information on the property...
关于你的物业的一些好消息
- Hello? - Hello, this is Sheldon Levene.
- 喂? - 我是沙利赖芬
Please listen closely... I only have a moment or so.
请仔细听好了... 我没多少时间
I can speak only to a Mrs. Nyborg.
我只可以和黎波太太说话
Oh, this is Mrs. Nyborg. Please listen closely, Mrs. Nyborg.
你就是啊 请用心听好了
I'm calling from Consolidated Properties of Arizona.
我是亚利桑拿地产公司的人
Our computer has chosen you from all of the many thousands
我们的电脑在众多提出申请的
who write in requesting information on our properties.
客人中选中了你
Now by federal law, as you probably know,
根据联邦法律 也许你也知道的
the prize must be awarded to you even if you are not engaged
即使你不在我们的土地发展计划上
in our land development plan.
奖品也是一定要送给你的
The only stipulation, of course, is that you and your husband
唯一的条件是你和你先生
must sign at the same time for the receipt of your prize.
要同时签收才能得到奖品
Now, I will be in the area tonight, possibly tomorrow.
我今晚或是明早会在你家附近
What do you think might be a convenient time to meet
你认为何时见你和你先生
with both you and your husband?
比较适当?
Of course I'll hold.
当然我可以等着
- Bunch of fucking nonsense, huh? - I can't close them.
- 全是废话 对吗? - 我没办法卖掉它们
- Nobody can close 'em. - They're old.
- 没人卖的掉 - 它们太旧了
They're ancient... a bunch of fucking nonsense.
它们太古老了... 全他妈的废话
Get some jerk to come in here...
找个白痴来这里...
Sometimes I think, "I wonder if I belong in this business."
有时我会想 "我真的适合干这行吗?"
Send a guy out there... no support, no confidence.
派人出去卖房子... 没有支持 没有信心
Then I say, "Nobody can close 'em."
然后我说 "没的卖的出去"
- Then I look at Roma. - Roma... fuck Roma.
- 然后我看着诺马 - 诺马 他妈的诺马
Had a freak... a little run of luck.
行为怪异... 还有点小运气
The leads are garbage.
这些生意都是垃圾
Then I say, "Why give him the good leads?
我说干吗把好生意都给他?
- He doesn't need 'em." - You going out?
- 他根本不需要 - 你出去吗?
Yeah. I have to go out. I can't make a sit.
对 我得出去 我没办法谈成生意
- Have you tried? - Yeah. Something's wrong with me.
- 试过了吗? - 我有点不对劲
What is it? I can't push through.
怎么了? 我有点撑不住了
Get your coat on. You're coming out with me.
穿上外套 和我一起出去吧
- Something in me. - Forget it.
- 我有点不对劲 - 忘了它吧
- I try, I try. - I said forget it, come on.
- 我不停的试着 - 我说别再想了
I can't close 'em.
我没办法谈成生意
Life.
生活
I swear to God, you work all your life...
我发誓 一辈子都要努力工作...
- Forget it, George. - Roma, so on...
- 别想了 乔治 - 像诺马这样的人...
- so gifted. - Gifted, my ass!
- 真是得天独厚啊 - 妈的!
- The guy gets a string of luck. - No, no, no.
- 这家伙真走运 - 不 不 不
The thing of it is, money's tight.
事情是这样的 钱很难赚
When times are tight, it don't do no good
当日子很艰难的时候
to throw around, "Just go out and sell."
"出去卖这卖那"也没什么好处
Threaten a man all you want, you can't whip a dead horse.
竭尽所能也不可能让匹死马跑起来
- Nope. - All this garbage...
- 是啊 - 这些垃圾生意...
"Sell 10,000, you win a Cadillac;
卖掉一万 你就能得到辆卡迪拉克
you lose, we're gonna fire your ass"? It's medieval.
失败的话我们就开除你? 这方法太古老了
- Yes. - It's wrong.
- 对 - 这是不对的
- Yes. - Yes it is,
- 对 - 是的
and you know who's responsible?
你知道该谁负这责任吗?
- Who? - You know who it is.
- 谁? - 你知道的
It's Mitch and Murray, 'cause it don't have to be this way.
米奇和默里公司 真不应是这样的
- No. - Look at Jerry Graff.
- 不 - 看看杰瑞格拉夫
He's clean, he's doing business for himself,
他有自己的生意
he's got that list... with the nurses?
他有那护士的名单
You see? That's thinking. Why take a 10% sales commission?
那才是应有的想法 为什么我们只能拿10%的佣金?
Why are we giving the rest away? What are we giving 90% for?
干吗要把90%给公司? 为了什么?
For nothing. For some jerk in the office,
结果那九成给了坐办公室的
telling us, "Get out there and close, go win a Cadillac."
对我们呼来喝去 "快出去做成生意 你就能得到那辆卡迪拉克"
Graff goes out and buys. He pays top dollar.
格拉夫出去后不是干的很成功吗?
- You see? - Yes.
- 你看到了? - 对
For the leads... that's thinking. Now, he's got the leads,
那些生意... 他手上有很多生意
he goes in business for himself. That's what? That's thinking.
他为自己赚钱 那才叫有头脑
Who... who's got a steady job,
谁有一份稳定的工作
a regular job, a couple of bucks nobody's touched?
一份稳定的收入?
Nurses.
护士
Graff goes and buys a fucking list of nurses. One grand...
格拉夫弄到份护士名单 只花了一千块
he paid two, I'll eat my hat. 4,000 or 5,000 nurses.
他花了两千的话我就把帽子吃了 四千或是五千个护士
- He's going wild. - He is?
- 他不发才怪呢 - 是吗?
- Yeah, he's doing very well. - I heard they were running cold.
- 对 他干的很好 - 我听说她们都不太热衷
- The nurses? - Yeah.
- 你是说护士? - 对
You hear a lot of things. He's doing very well.
你听到的倒不少 他的确干的很不错
- With River Oaks? - River Oaks, Brook Farms.
- 卖那些橡树? - 对 河木还有农场
All that shit. Somebody told me... you know what he's clearing, himself?
有人告诉我他一周
- 14, 15 grand a week. - Himself?
- 能卖出一万四到一万五的货 - 就他一个人?
That's what I'm saying. Why? He's got the leads.
我要说的就是这个 为什么?就因为他有足够的生意
He's got the good leads. What are we?
他手上有好生意 而我们呢?
We're sitting in the shit here. Why?
我们坐在这该死的破车里
Because we got to go to them to get them.
因为我们要问公司要生意
90% of our sales we're paying to the office for the leads.
我们付给公司九成的钱买生意
There's our leads, there's overhead, phones, a lot of stuff.
还有电话费等很多其他费用
What do you need? A telephone?
你需要什么?电话?
Some broad to say, "Good morning"? Nothing. It's the leads.
还有宽敞的地方用来见客? 只要有生意就可以了
The whole thing is the leads, you understand me?
关键在于要有生意 明白吗?
You can't sell to a void... you got to get a goddamn person.
你要先找到个客户
You get a lead, you get a person... I'll go sell 'em.
有生意有客户 然后我去卖
Otherwise, what do they want from my life?
要不他们想要什么?
Hello, Danny? Dan, it's Shel Levene.
你好吗 丹尼? 是我 沙利赖芬
Yeah, we spoke... last May I called you.
我们去年五月通过电话
I was in town from my estate in Rio Rancho, and...
我那时在亚利桑拿的
Arizona.
尼奥牧场
I wish we could have gotten together at that time.
我真希望那时可以联系上你
Danny, that piece of property I had for you has increased in value...
丹尼 上次我给你看的物业升值了
Grace, Grace, what was that figure? $ 76,000.
格雷斯 升到多少了? 七万六千美元
Oh, Danny, I wish you could have been in on it with me.
我希望你能考虑一下
Look, I'm here overnight... I have to go home tomorrow,
我会在这里过夜 明天就得回家
and I thought, after the interest you showed on the last trip, that...
我想 既然上次你很有兴趣
Hold it, Grace. Danny, I know that you're serious,
等等 格雷斯 我知道你是认真的
and because of that, I am going to shove my appointments around
所以我会推掉所有的约会
and make sure... oh, gee, I wish that...
以确定... 我希望...
All right, Danny. Yeah, all right.
好吧 丹尼
Going out tonight, Shelly?
今晚要出去吗 沙利?
What is this bullshit with the sales promotion?
今晚宣布的销售竞争计划是什么意思?
It isn't bullshit. It's the way it is.
就是那么回事
You're going to fire the bottom men on the list?
你会炒掉销售业绩最差的人?
That's the way it is and I don't make the rules.
游戏规则不是我定的
- The rules come from downtown. - I got a problem here, John.
- 是商业区那里定的规定 - 我有个小麻烦 约翰
- I'm closing up the office. - Come have a drink with me.
- 我要关门了 - 一起去喝一杯吧
- I've got to get home. - Do me the courtesy... five minutes?
- 我得回家去了 - 可以给我五分钟吗?
I am trying to get home for two hours.
我得在两小时内来回一趟
I got to go home, grab one hour with my kids, come back here,
我得回家看看孩子 然后回到这里
see if any of you closed a contract, take the contract...
看看有没有人谈成生意 搞定合约...
- How about one minute? - What is it?
- 就一分钟可以吗? - 什么事?
- I can't close these leads. - Then move on.
- 我没办法做成这些生意 - 那就继续试
Don't jump! Don't jump out of your manager bag a second.
别老摆出经理的架子
It's just two guys talking, am I right? We're just talking.
只是两个人私下谈谈 对吧?
You got the new leads. If you would give me... just hold on.
你手上有那些新生意 如果你可以给我...等等
The Glengarry leads are to be assigned only to closers.
格兰加利的生意只会 交给有能力的人去做
Hold on a second. If you give me the good leads...
等一下 如果你给我些好生意
You blew the last good one I gave you.
我上次给你的好生意你也搞砸了
No, no... hold on, will you?
等等好吗?
I did not blow 'em. One kicked out. One, I closed.
我没搞砸 我完成了其中一单
- You didn't close it. - Would you listen to me?
- 你没有 - 听我说好吗?
I closed that cocksucker! His ex! John, his ex!
我完成了那单生意! 都是他前妻干的好事 约翰!
I didn't even know he was married. The judge invalidated it.
我根本不知道他结过婚 法官判那交易无效
Shelly...
沙利...
What was that job, huh? Bad luck. That's all it was.
我只是不太走运
I pray you never find it... it runs in streaks.
我常祈祷让霉运远离你
That's what it's doing, that's all it does... streaks.
希望你事业一帆风顺
I pray that it misses you and that's all I have to say.
我祈求霉运离你远远的
Shit, I've got to eat. Williamson...
我得养家糊口啊
look at the sheets. Look at the sheets.
看看过去的销售记录
198 7, '88, '89... six months in '89... who's on top?
1987 88 89... 89年六个月 谁的销售额最高?
- Roma. - Under him?
- 诺马 - 他下面呢
- Moss. - Oh, bullshit, John!
- 莫斯 - 去他妈的 约翰!
April to September it's me... it's no fucking Moss.
四月到九月是我... 不是他妈的莫斯
Due respect, he's an order-taker.
不客气的说 他只会破坏生意
Talk... talks a good game, but look on the board, it's me.
但在报告板上是我
- Not lately it isn't. - Not late...
- 最近不是了 - 最近...
Well, lately... kiss my ass "lately."
最近... 去他妈的最近
You call Murray and you call Mitch... when we were on Peterson,
你打电话问问默里和米奇 我们跟着彼德逊时
who do you think bought the new car? Call Mitch. The Seville?
是谁买了新车? 打电话给米奇啊 塞维尔?
He came in here... "You bought that for me, fella."
他走进来说"你买给我的"
And out of what? Hey, look at me! Out of what? Nothing!
为什么? 看着我!
Cold calling. You want to talk about a sale?
你要和我谈销售额?
You are really beginning to burn my ass, kid.
你真要惹急我了 孩子
I can't get a lead, you... it was skill, John.
我拿不到生意 你... 这是技巧 约翰
It could be working for you... you want to throw it away.
我能为你工作 你却要抛弃我
- It isn't me. - It's not you...
- 那不是我的错... - 那不是你的错...
I wonder who it is. Who the fuck am I talking to?
我真怀疑我他妈的是在和谁说话
- I need the leads to sell. - After the contest. After the 30th.
- 我需要那些生意 - 过了月底 竞赛结束后
Bullshit, "After the contest."
废话 "竞赛结束后"
If I'm not on that board by the 30th, they're going to can my ass.
如果到三十号我还不能回到那榜上 他们就会炒掉我的
I need those leads and I need 'em now or I'm out.
我需要那些生意 现在就要 否则我便死定了
You're going to miss me. I swear to you, you will miss me.
你会想念我的 我发誓 你会挂念我的
Let me tell you something, Shelly.
让我告诉你吧 沙利
I do what I'm hired to do... you might do the same.
我只是做我该做的... 换了你是我也会这样做的!
- Jesus. - Now wait a second!
- 天啊! - 等一下!
I'm hired to watch the leads, to marshal my sales force.
我受雇来看着这些生意 分配销售任务
I'm given a policy. My job is to do that.
上头制订策略和规矩 我照章执行而已
Marshal your sales force?
分配你的销售任务?
Anybody falls below a certain mark, I'm directed.
任何人低于某销售量
I'm not permitted to give them the premium leads.
我就不能给他额外的好生意
How do they rise above that mark? With dreck?
那他们怎么提升业绩? 就靠那些垃圾生意?
With this toilet paper you're giving me?
靠你给我的这些厕纸一样的东西?
You give me one premium lead...
你给我一单好生意...
Do you know what the premium leads cost?
你知道那值多少钱吗?
Do I know what the premium leads cost?
我知道那值多少钱吗?
Yeah, I know what they cost.
我知道那值多少
I generated the sufficient dollar revenue to buy them.
我出了足够多的钱来取得生意
But I cannot sell shit!
可我没办法把垃圾卖出去!
Jesus. And I've seen these before, you know.
你知道我以前见过这些
Christ, I saw these back... Homestead...
天啊 现在又看见这些了... 农场...
1985, we pitched these cocksuckers Baywater.
1985 我们向这些 混蛋推销贝威特湖泊
They couldn't buy a fucking toaster. They're broke. They're deadbeats.
他们什么都买不起 他们一文不名
Just give me some leads that don't come out of a phone book.
给我一些好点的生意吧 不要那些随便凑电话本上找来的
You give me something hotter than that and I can close it.
给我些好点的生意吧 我一定能卖出去的
It's just a streak. I'm gonna turn it around.
我能改变现在这种局面的 现在只是碰上些小麻烦
Hey, I need your help.
嘿 我需要你的帮助
I can't do it, Shelly.
我不能那么做 沙利
John...
约翰...
I'll give you 10%.
我私底下给你10%怎么样
- Of what? - My end... what I close.
- 什么? - 我完成的生意的10%
You give me the premium leads, you're in for 10%, what I close.
给我些好生意 你就能拿到10%的钱
- And what if you don't close? - I will.
- 你卖不出去怎么办? - 我一定卖得出去的
- What if you don't close? - I will close.
- 你卖不出呢? - 我一定卖得出去的
What if you don't, you understand?
万一你卖不出去呢?
Then I'm fucked. You think you're the only guy with a family?
那我就完了 你以为只有你才有家人要养吗?
- You see what I'm saying? - John...
- 你明白我在说什么吗? - 约翰...
I step out and you don't close, then it's my job.
我帮了你忙 你却卖不出去的话 那我也会被炒掉的
- Then I'm fucked. - I will close!
- 然后我就完了 - 我一定能完成的!
Now, 10% John... I can get hot, you know that.
想想 10% 约翰 你知道我可以再次红起来的
- Not lately you can't. - That's defeatist... fuck it!
- 最近你的业绩很糟 - 去他妈的!
Go with me. Get on my side and let's do something.
站在我这边 帮我做点什么吧
You want to run this office? You heard what the man said...
你想运作这办公室? 你听到那家伙怎么说的
"Attack." Let's do something.
"进攻" 一起做点什么吧
- Huh? - 20%.
- 怎么样? - 我要20%
- All right. - And 50 bucks a lead.
- 好吧 - 另外五十美元买一单生意
- No? - Oh!
- 不成吗? - 哦!
Oh, shit.
妈的
Listen... I got to talk to you.
听着 我有话要跟你说
Permit me to do this a second. I'm older than you.
给我一秒钟吧 我比你年纪大
A man acquires a reputation on the street.
一个人需要有好的名声
What he does when he's up, what he does at other times...
当他高高在上时做了什么 其他时候又做了什么
I said, "10," you said, "No." You said, "20," I said, "Fine."
我说10% 你说不行 你说20% 我说成交
Now you want to throw this 50-buck thing in.
现在你要放弃50美元的生意
John, a good deal... has got to be one where both parties...
约翰 一桩好的交易得让当事人都...
Okay, okay, okay, fine... 20%, 50 bucks a lead. It's done.
好 20% 每张单子50元 成交
Let's go out. We make some money.
一起去赚钱吧
I got bills to pay. I want two sits tonight
我还有很多帐单要付 我今晚要两单生意
and I want the good leads... the Glengarry leads... two.
我要格兰加利的好生意 两单
Two, John, because I am going to close 'em both.
约翰 我会把它们都卖掉的
It's a long road with no turning, pally.
已经没有回头的余地了
Huh? Okay. Now, let's go.
走吧
I've got to go back to the office to get 'em.
我得回办公室拿单子
Go on, let's go. This is what I was saying, John.
好的 一起去吧 我不是说了吗 约翰
All you need, a little boost, you turn a streak around.
只要有人帮你一把就能渡过难关
Am I right? Good, huh? Huh, good?
我说的对吗?
What?
什么?
- What? - Two leads, 100 bucks.
- 什么? - 两单生意 一百元
- Now? - Now, yes. When?
- 现在就要给? - 对 不然你以为什么时候给?
- Shit, John. - I wish I could.
- 妈的 约翰 - 我希望我可以
You fucking asshole.
你这该死的混蛋
I don't have it... I don't...
我现在没那么多钱...
I'll bring it in the office in the morning.
我会明早拿到办公室给你的
- I'll be coming with the sales. - Nope.
- 我还会带着合约一起来的 - 不行
I can't fucking believe this.
我真不敢相信
All right, here's...
那好吧 这里是...
20...30...
二十 三十
Jesus, here's the 30. I'll bring the rest in tomorrow.
这里是三十 我明早给你剩下的
We got to do this, huh, pal? For Christ's sake!
以主的名义 你就帮帮我吧!
No.
不行
- My daughter... - I can't do it, Shelly.
- 我的女儿... - 我不能那么做 沙利
I got to tell you something. It wasn't so long ago,
我有事要告诉你 就是不久以前的事
I'd pick up the phone and call Murray... I got your job.
我打电话给默里 替你找到了这份工作
"Murray, the kid is burning my ass." "Shelly, he's gone."
"默里 就帮帮那孩子" "沙利 他走了"
You are gone before I'm back from lunch.
我吃完午饭回来你已经走了
Bought him a trip to Bermuda once.
我为了你请他到百慕大旅行
- I've got to go. - All right, hey.
- 我要走了 - 好吧 嘿
Give me... I'll take two more of the old leads.
再给我两单老的生意
- I gave you two today. - One is a bust-out, John!
- 今天我给了两单了 - 一单明显是垃圾 约翰!
- The other ain't home! - Shelly...
- 还有单人不在家! - 沙利...
I promise you, I've been on the phone... I know.
我向你保证 我有打电话去
No more leads today... two per day. You've got yours.
今天没新的生意了 每天两单 你拿到你的生意了
All right.
好吧
- All right? - Sure.
- 行了吗? - 行了
We will do that... other thing.
这事明天再说吧
I guess I left my wallet in my room.
我想我把钱包忘在房间里了
Deadbeats. Deadbeats, all of 'em.
全他妈的是混蛋
My mistake. I shouldn't have took the leads.
是我的错 我不应该接那些生意
- You had to. - Yeah? Why?
- 你不得不接 - 是吗? 为什么?
- To get on the... - To get on the board, yeah.
- 为了... - 为了回到销售榜上
How am I gonna get on the board trying to sell a doctor?
我能怎么做?卖给医生吗?
Two regular, two chocolate donuts.
照旧 再加两份巧克力圈
Give me the same thing to go. And don't try and sell an Indian.
只会给我那些老的垃圾生意 不要试着去卖给印第安人
I will never try to sell an Indian.
我从不尝试卖给印第安人
These names come up... you ever get 'em... "Patel"?
你有见过这些名字吗?"柏特"?
- You ever get 'em? - I think I had one once.
- 你有拿到过吗? - 我想我拿到过一次
You had one, you'd know it... "Patel."
你拿过的话一定有印象..."柏特"
They keep coming up. I don't know.
他们会一直找你
They like to talk to salesmen. They're lonely.
他们喜欢和经纪谈天 他们太寂寞了
They like to feel superior... never bought a fucking thing.
他们喜欢觉得自己高人一等... 却从来不买任何东西
I don't know. Come down the line...
我不清楚 医生 律师 印弟安人
doctors, lawyers, Indians... times are tight. It's tight.
都属于这一类 日子真难过
Pressure's just too great. Man can't work all of 'em.
压力太大了 一个人不能只知道工作
You go in the door... I got to close this fucker or I don't eat lunch,
我得走进去 和这些混蛋打交道 或者不吃午餐
or I don't win a Cadillac. We work too hard, George.
不然就赢不到那卡迪拉克 我们工作太卖力了 乔治
Remember when we were... when we were selling Glen Ross Farms?
还记得我们推销根罗农场的时候吗?
Didn't we sell a bunch of that?
我们不是推销过吗?
- They came in... - They fucked it up.
- 他们便来了... - 他们把一切都弄糟了
- They did. - They killed the goose. And now...
- 没错 - 他们杀了所有的鹅 现在...
- We're stuck with this... - Stuck with this fucking shit.
- 我们就困死在这里 - 被这些该死的东西困死
- This shit. - It's too...
- 他妈的 - 这...
- It is. - You get a bad month...
- 没错 - 你真不斯文
they put you on this board. Some contest board.
他们把你放在销售竞争榜上
- It's not right. - It's not right to the customers.
- 这是不好的 - 对客户来说是不好
I know, it's... hey. What did I learn as a kid on Western?
我知道 但... 当我还是小孩时学到一个道理
Don't sell a guy one car. Sell him five cars over 15 years.
不要向一个人卖一辆车就满足了 而要他十五年买五辆车
- That's right. - You're goddamn right, it's right.
- 说的对 - 没错
Guys come in... "Oh, the blah, blah, blah. I know what I'll do.
那些家伙走进来 乱说一气 我知道我该怎么做
I'll go out and rob everybody blind and go to Argentina
我会出门 打劫所有瞎子 然后逃去阿根廷
'cause nobody ever thought of this before."
因为以前从没有人这样想过
So they kill the goose and the man's worked all his life...
他们杀了所有的鹅 那人一辈子都在不停的工作...
- That's right. - He's got to cower in his boots...
- 没错 - 最后也只有退到自己的靴子里去
Boots, yes...
没错 靴子...
For some fucking "Sell 10,000, win the steak knives."
就因为有些混蛋说 "卖出一万 就可以拿到一套牛扒刀具"
- What do you do? - What can you do?
- 你怎么做? - 你可以做什么?
What can you do if you don't have the leads?
没有那些生意你可以做什么?
If you do not have the goddamn leads!
如果没那样该死的生意!
Mr. Spannel? Sheldon Levene.
史先生吗? 我是沙利赖芬
I was speaking to your wife earlier?
我早前跟你太太通过电话了
Come in.
进来吧
- "Cats and dogs," huh? - Yeah.
- 雨下的真大啊 - 对
Oh, "cats and dogs."
雨下的可真大
Oh, I see you're interested in fishing.
你一定很喜欢钓鱼吧
- Yeah. - I've fished myself... many years.
- 没错 - 我喜欢一个人钓鱼 有好几年了
Muskee, Wisconsin. Ooh, a beauty.
威斯康星产的 真棒啊
- Where's the missus? - Out at the PTA.
- 史太太呢? - 去参加家长委员会了
What was this in reference...?
你来有何贵干?
I spoke to your wife earlier on the phone.
我跟你太太早前在电话里谈过
I called, I'm in town with Rio Rancho.
我是为了尼奥牧场的事来城里的
Yes, I'm sorry. She said you had some sort of award?
哦 我想起来了 她说过你有奖品要给我们
Yes, I was speaking to the people in my sales organization...
我和我公司的人谈过
my representatives in this area... and Mr. Spannel...
我是指负责这一区的同事 史先生...
your name is Larry. Mind if I call you Larry?
你叫拉里对吗? 我可以这么称呼你吗?
All right, Larry. We had a consultant,
好的 拉里 我们有个顾问
and he made me... he made me an offer.
他给我这样一个优惠
He offered me $230,000 to promote a sales plan...
他给了我二十三万来做销售计划
to present investment opportunities in Rio Rancho to the public.
向大众宣传我们在尼奥牧场的投资机会
Well, I said, "Hell, let me save you the 230,
我说 我可以为你省下那二十三万
and pass the savings along to the investor."
然后将这些钱留给投资者
My people immediately said, "Whoa, how do you do that?
那家伙马上问我可以怎样做?
How can you present investment opportunities
不靠电视宣传 不靠杂志广告
without television, without magazine ads?"
怎么吸引投资者?
I said, "You take something this good,
我说 你就这样做
you go to a man... has invested in the past...
你去找以前投资过的人
you go to him direct and offer the money to him... rebate.
把这笔钱作为回扣给他
And don't give it to this expert."
不要把钱给狗屁推销专家
So you're here to sell me some land?
你来是向我推销土地的?
No, I wouldn't try to sell you...
不 我不是来向你推销土地的
I leave that to the salesmen and people who want to own land.
这些就交给房产经纪还有 那些有兴趣买地的人去做吧
I think something has to be fed,
我认为有些东西
watered and painted, but don't invest in it.
总得有人去打理 但不要在它上面投资
That motto has stood me in good stead.
这座右铭让我受益非浅
- Mister... - Just call me Shelly.
- 先生... - 叫我沙利吧
I have never been afraid of familiarity.
我从不介意亲切点的
I'm walking out the door. I've got to pick up my wife at the...
我要出门去接我太太了
Let's take my car. We'll pick her up together.
开我的车去吧 我们一起去接她
Spoke to the little woman on the phone... can't wait to meet her.
跟她在电话里谈过后真想见见她
No, we're going over to our relatives'.
我们还要去亲戚那里
- She didn't say anything about that. - I'm sure she forgot.
- 她没提起过 - 我很抱歉她肯定是忘了
- I'm on a plane to Florida... - I'm sorry if we put you out.
- 我还要搭飞机去佛罗里达 - 如果耽误了你的事 我很抱歉
You didn't put me out. I'm just trying to think, Larry.
拉里 你没麻烦到我 我只是在想
You know, that's the only parcel that I've got.
你知道 我只挑选了你一个人
You know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna go back to the computer,
你知道我会怎么做? 我会回去打开电脑
I'm gonna pull another one, and we're gonna speak to your relatives, too.
再选另一个人 我们也可以跟你的亲友们谈谈的
- No, no, no. - C'mon, you're a busy man, so am I.
- 不用了 - 你是个大忙人 我也是啊
My God, I'm in the act of giving a gift away.
天啊 我是在送礼啊
Look, I don't want to buy land. I don't want to invest in land.
我不想买地 我不想在土地上投资
I have nothing. She took the call without my knowledge.
我没钱投资 她没告诉我就接了电话
I have no business that I wish to transact.
我没有生意要做
I don't want to tell you how to handle your wife.
我不是想告诉你怎么对待你太太
My wife filled in a form, and we have been plagued for the last year...
我太太去年填了张表 然后去年不停的有人骚扰我们
That's the situation I'm trying to alleviate, Larry.
我就是来帮你解决这种状况的
No, no. Do you understand?
不 不 你明白吗?
Thank you. No.
谢谢 我不买
- Roma, man... he don't care. - He don't care.
- 诺马...他才不在乎呢 - 他是不在乎
He's sitting on top of the world. He's got good leads, good prospects.
他有好的生意 光明的前途 高高在上
- Sales, sales. - Sales contests.
- 销量 销量 - 销量竞赛
- That's what I'm saying. - Times turn hard, they bounce you out.
- 我就是要说这个 - 日子越来越难过 他们把你拒之门外
If they bounce you with no confidence...
任何自信也不留给你
That's what I'm saying. That's what I'm saying to you.
那正是我对你所说的
If they get you on a bad beat...
如果你这次又失败了
and you got to go out there, get a new job...
就得出去另找份新的工作
- With no... - With no confidence...
- 可是你已经没有... - 没有自信...
Yes.
对
I'll tell you what the hard part is... to stop thinking like a goddamn slave.
我可以告诉你最困难的是什么 就是很难停止想象自己是个狗奴才
You say the Nazis in Europe... "If they came in my door"...
你说欧洲的纳粹党 "如果他们走进我的屋子"...
bullshit, the time is now. What do you do now?
胡说 重要的是现在 你现在该做什么?
Some guy pissing in your face. Cocksucker...
有人在你脸上撒尿 该死的...
wants to break your rice bowl.
想打烂你的饭碗
Mitch and Murray, fuck you. What I say... fuck you!
去他妈的米奇和默里 去他妈的!
Sitting on the good leads.
只会坐在好生意上面
George, we're men here.
乔治 我们是真正的男人
Yes.
对
And I'll tell you... I'll tell you what the hard part is.
我会告诉你最困难的是什么
- What? - Starting up.
- 什么? - 起步的时候最困难
Standing up. Breaking free of this bullshit,
站起身来 不再花时间说这些废话
this enslavement to some guy, 'cause he's got the upper hand.
不再受某人奴役 就因为他高高在上
This is the difference... listen to me, George.
这就是不同之处 听我说 乔治
Now Jerry Graff went into business for himself.
现在谢利格拉夫自己做生意了
He said, "I'm going on my own." And he was free, you understand me?
他说"我要靠自己的" 他现在自由了 你明白我的意思吗?
I'll tell you... I'll tell you what somebody should do.
我会告诉你应该怎么做人
What?
什么?
Somebody should stand up and strike back.
应该有人站出来反击
Somebody should do something to them.
应该有人对他们做点什么
- What? - Something to pay them back.
- 你说什么? - 做些回报他们的事情
Someone should hurt them, Mitch and Murray.
要让米奇和默里吃点苦头
- Somebody should hurt them? - Yeah.
- 吃点苦头? - 对
- How? - Someone should do something
- 怎么做? - 我们应该从内部入手
- to hurt them where they live. - What?
- 让他们吃点苦头 - 什么?
Someone should rob the office. That's what I'm saying.
应该去打劫办公室 那正是我要说的
If we were that kind of guy to hold up the joint and trash it,
如果我们把办公室弄的乱七八糟
it looks like robbery, we take the leads out of the files
看起来就象是打劫 我们拿走那些该死的生意
and we go to Jerry Graff.
然后到谢利格拉夫那里去
And we take the fucking Glengarry leads! Huh?
我们拿走格兰加利的那些生意!
Yeah, Mr. Nyborg? Ah, Mr. Nyborg, Sheldon Levene.
黎波先生? 我是沙利赖芬
I was speaking to your wife earlier. That's right.
我早前跟你太太谈过 没错
I'd like to speak to you about awarding you your prize.
我想跟你谈谈那奖品的事
We're coming to the end of our fiscal year,
我们公司的财政年度快要结束了
I'd really like to get it off the books before...
我希望能在那以前...
yes, the prize for Consolidated Properties.
对 给处理好的物业的奖品
The information you requested on Rio Rancho.
你要求的尼奥农场的资料
Now, I'm in town only for... well, let me see.
我只能在城里待...让我看看
I suppose I could swing by tonight. Yes. Uh-huh.
我想我可以留到今晚
When do you think it might be more convenient?
你认为什么时候见面比较方便?
As I said, I could swing by tonight...
我说了 我可以留到今晚
well, of course, you speak to your wife.
当然 你先和你太太商量一下吧
Grace, I'm gonna need
格雷斯 帮我订张
a first-class seat, passport, 10,000 in cash,
头等舱机票 还有护照和一万元现金
put that with the negotiable papers, if you would.
和协议书一起
And put me on the telex hookup... yes?
放在传真机上 喂?
Well, when do you think Mrs. Nyborg might be back?
你看你太太什么时候会回来?
All train compartments smell vaguely of shit.
所有的车厢都有股臭味
It gets so you don't mind it.
你不在意的话就闻不到
That's the worst thing that I can confess.
那是我遇到的最糟糕的事情
You know how long it took me to get there? A long time.
你知道我到那里要多久吗? 很长时间
When you die you're gonna regret the things you don't do.
你要死的时候便会后悔 还有很多没做过的事
You think you're queer? I'm gonna tell you something.
你以为自己很怪 让我告诉你
We're all queer. You think you're a thief? So what?
我们全都很怪 你以为自己是贼?那又怎么样?
You get befuddled by a middle-class morality?
你为中产阶级的道德感到迷惑?
Get shut of it. Shut it out.
少来这套了
You cheat on your wife, you did it. Live with it.
你骗了你太太
You fuck little girls, so be it.
你跟小女孩上床 没什么大不了的
There's an absolute morality? Maybe.
世上有绝对的道德吗? 也许有吧
And then what?
然后又怎么样?
If you think there is, go ahead, be that thing.
如果你认为有 就照做啊
Bad people go to hell? I don't think so.
坏人死后要下地狱? 我不这么想
You think that, act that way.
你怎么想就怎么做吧
A hell exists on earth? Yes. I won't live in it.
世上有地狱吗? 有我也不会住进去
That's me.
那就是我
Did you ever take a dump, made you feel like you slept for 12 hours?
你有试过在垃圾堆中待过 然后觉得就象睡了十二个钟头?
- Did I...? - Yes.
- 我有没有呢? - 对
- I don't know. - Or a piss?
- 我不知道 - 或者尝尝小便?
Great meals fade in reflection.
再丰盛的大餐也会在回忆中淡去
Everything else gains. Do you know why?
所有事都这样 你知道为什么吗?
'Cause it's only food. This shit we put in us,
因为世上只有食物 我们每天吃进去的东西
keeps us going... it's only food.
让我们有力气... 只是食物
The great fucks you may have had,
也许你曾有过美妙的作爱
what do you remember about them?
你还记得她们吗?
- What do I remember? - Yeah.
- 我又还记得些什么? - 对
I don't know. For me,
我不知道 对我来说
I'm saying what it is, it's probably not the orgasm.
我会说大概不是高潮
Some broad's forearm on your neck,
或许是手臂的紧紧拥抱
something her eyes did. There was this sound she made.
也许是她的一个眼神 还有她的叫声
Or it's me in the... I'm telling you...
我告诉你
I'm in bed the next day, she brought me cafe au lait,
第二天早上我躺在床上 她端给我杯牛奶咖啡
gives me a cigarette, my balls feel like concrete.
还给我一支烟 我的心中感到很满足
Eh?
恩?
What I'm saying, what is our life?
我想说的是 什么是生活?
Our life is looking forward or it's looking back.
我们的生活就是向前看 或是向后
That's it. That's our life.
就那样 那就是我们的生活
Where's the moment?
那时刻在哪儿?
And what is it we're so afraid of?
我们究竟在害怕什么?
Loss. What else?
失败还有什么?
The bank closes, we get sick, my wife died on a plane?
是银行倒闭 我们生病了 或是我太太飞机失事了?
The stock market collapsed? What of these things happen?
或是股票市场崩盘?
None of them. We worry anyway. Why?
没有一件事发生过 但我们却不断的担心为什么?
What could we get for them?
我们从它们那里可以得到什么?
- For them? - For the leads.
- 什么? - 我是说生意
What could we get for the leads?
从那些生意里我们可得到什么利益?
I don't know. 10 bucks a throw. 15 maybe. I don't know.
我不知道 十块或许十五块一单吧
For the leads, you're saying? Say somebody took them,
你是在说生意吗? 如果有人拿了这些生意
- went to Jerry Graff? - Yeah. How many leads do we have?
- 到谢利格拉夫那里去呢? - 我们手上有多少生意?
The Glengarry? The premium leads?
你是指格兰加利的生意? 最好的那些?
I've got to think they've got 500. Say 500 leads.
我猜应该有500单吧 500单生意
You're saying a fella could take those leads and sell them to Graff?
你是说有人会 把那些生意卖给格拉夫?
The leads to Graff. Yes. I was saying... yeah.
卖给格拉夫 对 没错
A guy could take... like anything else, it seems to me,
有人可以拿走这些生意 就象拿走别的东西那样
that is negotiable, a guy could sell them.
谈妥后就卖掉它们
- How do you know he'd buy them? - Because I worked for him.
- 你怎么知道格拉夫会买? - 因为我曾为他工作
- You didn't talk to him? - No. What do you mean?
- 你没有跟他说? - 没有你什么意思?
- Did I talk to him about this? - Yeah.
- 你问我和他提起过这事吗? - 对
Are you just talking about this, or are we just talking about it?
你只是说说而已 还是我们在正式谈这事?
- Just speaking about it. - Speaking about it as an idea?
- 只是随便说说而已 - 当做个主意谈谈?
- Yes. - We're not actually talking about it.
- 对 - 我们并没有在正式谈这事
- No. - Talking about it as a robbery.
- 对 没有 - 我们没有正式谈论这劫案
As a robbery? No.
劫案?不
Hey.
嘿
So all this... you didn't actually call Graff?
你并没有跟格利夫谈过?
- You didn't talk to him? - Not actually, no.
- 对不对? 没有和他谈过 - 是的
- You didn't? - No, not actually.
- 没和他谈过? - 没有
- Did you? - What did I say?
- 你没有? - 我说什么了?
- What did you say? - I said, "Not actually."
- 你说什么了? - 我说:实际上没有谈过
Fuck you care, George? We're just talking.
那又怎么样 乔治? 我们只是说说罢了
- We are? - Yes.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Because it's a crime. - Robbery. That's right.
- 因为那样做是犯罪 - 没错 是抢劫
It is a crime.
这是犯罪
- It's also very safe. - You're actually talking about this.
- 但也非常安全 - 你实际上是在讲真的
- That's right. - You're going to steal the leads.
- 没错 - 你想劫走这些生意
- Have I said that? - Are you?
- 我有这样说吗? - 你有吗?
- Did I say that? - Did you talk to Graff?
- 我有说吗? - 你有和格拉夫谈过吗?
- What did I say? - What did he say?
- 我怎么说的? - 他怎么说的?
What did he say?
他怎么说的?
He'd buy them.
他会买下那些生意
You're gonna steal...
你会去偷...
you're gonna steal the Glengarry leads and sell them to Graff?
你会去偷格兰加利的那些生意 然后卖给格拉夫?
- Yes. - What's he gonna pay?
- 对 - 他肯出多少钱?
He figures there's 500 leads, let's say 10 bucks apiece,
他知道有五百单生意 每单十块钱
- that's $2,500 each. - Each?
- 那就是每人两千五百块 - 每人?
- "Each"? - That's right, George.
- 每人? - 没错 乔治
- You're saying me? - No, you and me.
- 你是在说我? - 不 是你和我
Yeah. That's exactly what I'm saying. $2,500 apiece.
那正是我想说的 你和我一人两千五百块
You and me for one night's work, and a job with Graff
只要一晚的工作 还能到格拉夫那里工作
- working the premium leads. - A job with Graff?
- 处理那些好的生意? - 为格拉夫工作?
- Is that what I said? - He'd give me a job?
- 我是这么说的吧? - 他会给我份工作?
He could take you on. Yes.
他会照顾你的 对
Hello?
喂?
I was dialing the direct line to my daughter's room.
我是直接打我女儿的房间的
Sheldon Levene. She's in...
我是沙利赖芬 她是在二十...
well, yeah, I'm sure she's asleep. But... where's the duty nurse?
我知道她已睡了 但...当值的护士呢?
They canceled her... well, let me talk...
他们取消了值夜班的护士... 那让我和...
who am I speaking to?
等等 你是谁?
I'll have the money there tomorrow.
我明天就会拿钱来
It's a big decision, George.
这是个重大的决定 乔治
At times a guy has got to make one.
一个人总要做些决定的
It's a big decision and it's a big reward.
这是个重大的决定 也会有大的回报
$2,500 and a job, it's a big reward for one night's work.
两千五百块和一份好工作 对于一晚的工作确是个大回报
Yes.
对
Sometimes a guy...
有时候 人会...
sometimes, a man if he wants a reward...
有时人会很想得到回报
That's absolutely right.
那是决对正确的
He'll do one thing, one thing on one night.
他会在某天晚上做某件事
That's absolutely right. The thing is, it's got to be tonight.
那是绝对正确的 重要的是这要今晚就做
What?
什么?
What, what? The leads ain't going to leave?
那些生意单子就不会离开吗?
They bring those leads up, wave them under your nose,
他们只是拿这些单子在你面前晃晃
tomorrow they take them downtown, parcel them out.
明天就会拿回商业区去
A guy wants those leads, he's gonna have to get them tonight.
有人要这些生意的单子 他想今晚就拿到手
Tonight is the thing. Talk about a chance.
今晚是个关键的晚上 是个好机会
It's when a chance presents itself.
大好机会就在眼前
You got to go in there tonight.
所以今晚你一定要进去办公室
- You. - I'm sorry?
- 是你 - 你说什么?
- You. - Me?
- 你 - 我
You have to go in. You have to get the leads.
你要进去办公室 拿到那些生意的单子
- I do? - It's not something for nothing.
- 为什么是我? - 你总要做些什么的
I took you in on this. You have to go. It's your thing.
我给你这么个机会 你一定得去 这是你的事
I've made a deal with Graff. I can't go in.
我已和格拉夫谈好了 我不能亲自去拿
I've spoken out on this too much. I've got a big mouth.
我已经说的太多了 我的嘴巴太大了
"The fucking leads," et cetera, "the tight-ass company," blah, blah.
"该死的生意" "该死的公司"
- They'll know when you go to Graff. - What will they know?
- 你去格拉夫那里的话他们会知道一切的 - 他们知道什么?
That I stole the leads? I didn't steal the leads.
会知道我偷了那些生意? 我没有偷那些生意
I'm gonna go to the movies. Then I'm gonna have a late drink
我会去看电影 然后去科摩酒巴
- at the Como Inn with a friend. - Dave.
- 和一个朋友喝点酒 - 戴夫
Yes?
怎么了?
You want me to break into the office tonight and steal the leads?
你要我半夜进办公室偷那些生意?
- Yes. - No.
- 对 - 不行
- Oh, yes, George. - What does that mean?
- 哦 你行的 乔治 - 什么意思?
Listen to this. I have an alibi. I'm going to the Como Inn.
听好了 我有不在场证据 我会去科摩酒巴喝酒
Why? Why? The place gets robbed,
为什么? 办公室被打劫了
they're going to come looking for me. Why? Because I probably did it.
他们会来找我 为什么?因为也许是我干的
Let me ask you this... are you going to turn me in?
那我问你个问题 你会出卖我吗?
What if you don't get caught?
你没被抓住又怎样?
They come to you, are you going to turn me in?
他们来盘问你 你会出卖我吗?
- Why would they come to me? - They're going to come to everybody.
- 他们为什么会来盘问我? - 他们会盘问每一个人
- Why would I do it? - You wouldn't, George.
- 我有什么动机这么做? - 你没有 乔治
That's why I'm talking to you now. They come to you,
所以我才跟你说这事 他们盘问你
- are you going to turn me in? - No.
- 你会出卖我吗? - 不会
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
- 你确定? - 确定
Uh-huh. George... when they come to me,
乔治... 他们来盘问我
if I have to go in there, and if I get caught...
如果我得进去偷生意 如果我被抓住
- they come to me... - You don't have to go in.
- 他们来盘问我... - 你不需要亲自去偷的
I have to go in, see? That's something I have to do.
我一定得进去偷 那是我一定要做的事
- Why? - Why?
- 为什么? - 为什么?
Are you going to give me $ 7,500?
你能给我七千五百块吗?
75? I thought we were splitting five grand.
我还以为总共只有五千块
I lied, all right? Your end is 25, my end is my own concern.
我撒谎了 你只能拿到两千五 我那份就不用你操心了
Now, stick with me here. If they come to me,
问题就在我这里 如果他们来找我
I'm caught, they're going to ask me who were accomplices.
我被抓了 他们会问我谁是同谋
- Me. - Absolutely.
- 我 - 没错
That's ridiculous.
那太荒谬了
To the law, you're an accessory before the fact.
从法律上来说 事实上你是同谋
- I didn't ask to be. - Tough luck, because you are.
- 我没有说想干的 - 很幸运 你就是同谋
- Because you told me about it? - That's right.
- 就因为你告诉我了? - 没错
Why are you doing this to me, Dave?
你为什么要这样对我 戴夫?
Why are you talking this way to me? I don't understand.
你干吗要这样和我说? 我不明白
- Why are you doing this at all? - None of your fucking business.
- 为什么你要这样做? - 全不关你的事
Just in or out? You tell me.
做还是不做 告诉我
You're out, you take the consequences.
不做的话后果自负
- I do? - That's right.
- 是吗? - 没错
- And why is that? - Because you listened.
- 为什么会那样? - 因为你听了
Well, when will Mrs. Nyborg be back?
黎波太太什么时候回来?
You know, I hate to keep calling you this late, Bruce,
我不喜欢这么晚还打电话给你
but I feel a responsibility, I must say. When you have...
但我觉得我有责任告诉你...
You know, they say, "You don't buy it, you rent it."
他们说"你没有买下 你是租的"
- Huh? - The thing.
- 哦? - 什么都是租的
You really... what do you keep?
你还留下些什么?
I mean, you don't keep anything, really.
我是说 什么也没留下
- No. - Security.
- 没有 - 安全感
Things. Things.
安全感
- You know? - Mm-hmm.
- 你知道吗? - 嗯
It's just... you try to stave off insecurity.
你试着除去不安全的感觉
You can't do it.
但你做不到
No. That's what I'm telling you.
那正是我想告诉你的
Stocks, bonds, objects of art, real estate, what are they?
股票 债券 艺术品 房地产 它们是什么?
An opportunity. To what? To make money?
一个机会 什么机会?赚钱的机会?
Perhaps. To lose money? Perhaps.
也许吧输钱的机会? 也许是吧
To indulge and to learn about ourselves? Perhaps.
去放纵自己 认识自己? 也许是吧
So fucking what? What is it? They're an opportunity.
那又怎么样?这到底是什么? 它们都是个机会
That's all they are. They're an event.
它们就是那样 它们是个事件
A guy comes to you, you make a call. You send in a card,
有人走到你跟前 你打电话给他 你递上名片
I have these properties I would like for you to see.
我有些物业我想你会有兴趣看看的
What does this mean? What do you want it to mean?
这什么意思? 你想它有什么意思?
You see what I'm saying?
你明白我在说什么吗?
Things happen to you.
事情就这样发生了
Glad I met you.
很高兴认识你
I'm glad I met you, James.
我也很高兴认识你 詹姆士
I want to show you something.
我想给你看些东西
It may mean something to you, it may not.
你可能会有兴趣 也许不会
I don't know. I don't know anymore.
我不知道 我再也不知道
What is that? Florida.
那是什么? 佛罗里达
Glengarry Highlands. Florida.
格兰加利高地 佛罗里达
Bullshit. And maybe that's true.
废话 也许那是对的
And that's what I said.
那正是我说的
But look at this.
但看看这个
What is this? This is a piece of land.
这是什么? 这是一块地
Listen to what I'm going to tell you now.
仔细听好我要告诉你的事
- What happened? - Where do you work?
- 发生什么事了? - 你在哪里工作?
I work, yes. I work here.
我就在这里上班
- What is it? What happened? - Robbery.
- 发生什么事了? - 盗窃
Williamson. Williamson, did they get the contracts?
威林逊 他们抢走了合约没有?
All right, tell me. Now. Tell me.
快告诉我
- They stole the contracts? - Excuse me, sir.
- 他们有没有偷走合约? - 对不起 先生
- Did they get my contract? - Excuse me, fella.
- 他们有没有偷走我的合约? - 对不起 伙计
- Did they? - Would you excuse us?
- 有没有? - 能先出去一下吗?
Don't fuck with me, fella. I'm talking about a Cadillac car
别惹我 伙计 我是在说你欠我的
- that you owe me. - They didn't get your contract.
- 那辆卡迪拉克房车 - 他们没偷走你的合约
- I filed it before I left. - They didn't get my contracts?
- 我离开前都放好了 - 他们没偷走我的合约?
They got... excuse me.
他们偷走了...失陪
Fuck.
妈的
Fuck, fuck, fuck! Williamson!
妈的 威尔逊!
- Williamson, open the fucking door. - Who are you?
- 快开门! - 这家伙是谁?
- They didn't get the contracts. - Did they?
- 他们没偷走合约 - 是吗?
They got... listen to me. They got some of them.
听我说 他们偷走了一部分合约
- Some of them? - Who told you?
- 一部分? - 谁告诉你的?
Who told me? Who told me we had a robbery?
谁告诉我这里发生盗窃案的?
We got a fucking board up on the window.
窗户那边有个该死的排行榜
Who is this? Yes. Yes, I confess. I did it.
这家伙是谁? 我承认 是我干的
Now, leave me a second here, please.
请给我些许时间
- Okay, now, talk to me. - I'm still trying to sort it out.
- 现在告诉我 - 我还在清点合约
- So far... - Talk to me. Talk to me.
- 到目前为止... - 告诉我
They got some of the contracts?
他们偷走了一部分合约?
Lingk. James Lingk, which I closed last night.
我昨晚完成的那单 詹姆士林克
- You closed it last night? - Yes.
- 你昨晚完成了? - 是的
- I filed it. It went down. - You filed it?
- 我送去城里了 - 你放好了?
- James Lingk? - Yes.
- 詹姆士林克的那单? - 是的
- It was sent downtown? - Yes, all right?
- 送到城里去了? - 是的 有问题吗?
I filed it last night. It went to the bank.
昨晚我放好 送去银行了
- It went downtown, all right? - You filed it?
- 送了去商业区 行了吗? - 你确定?
Then I'm over the fucking top, you owe me a Cadillac.
那我就是排行榜的第一名 你欠我一辆卡迪拉克
- I don't... - I don't want to hear any shit.
- 我... - 我不想听废话
I don't give a shit. Lingk puts me over the top.
我什么也不理 林克的生意让我登上了榜首
You filed it. It went downtown. Now you owe me the car.
你送去商业区那里了 现在你欠我辆卡迪拉克
- The robbery makes difficult... - Fuck you! You owe me the car!
- 这次盗窃使... - 去你的!你欠我辆车!
See, 'cause this is how we keep score, "bubby."
"因为我们就是这样保持业绩的"
You told me, "Close thus, and so you get the car."
你跟我说 "完成这单生意 车就是你的了"
- I got it. - Would you excuse us, please?
- 我做到了 - 请你走开一会儿吗?
You hear what I said? Do you hear what I said?
你听到我说什么了吗?
Hey, pal! Your excuses are your own!
嘿 伙计! 我才不管你的狗屁借口!
"Recontact James Lingk.
联络詹姆士林克
6:00 p.m. Morton Grove." Ah-ha.
晚上六点 莫顿园林
When do you expect her in?
她几点到?
This is Ricky Roma from last night.
我是昨晚的理查德诺马
She'll remember. Just, just... wait a minute!
她会记得的 等等!
Just to say... to thank her for a wonderful time.
只要说...多谢昨晚的美妙时光
Thank you. I'll call back later. Thank you.
谢谢 我迟些再打来 谢谢
They should check if we're insured.
他们该看看是否买了保险
Uh-huh.
是呀
"10:00 p.m., Octavia."
"晚上十点 奥塔维亚"
Please don't leave. I'm going to talk to you.
请别走 有话要问你
- What's your name? - Are you talking to me?
- 你叫什么名字? - 你是在和我说话吗?
- That's right. - My name is Richard Roma.
- 没错 - 我叫理查德诺马
I... you know, they should be insured.
你知道 他们应该买保险的
- What do you care? - Then they wouldn't be so upset.
- 你担心什么? - 那他们就不会那么沮丧
They wouldn't be so upset.
他们就不会那么不开心
- Mitch and Murray. - Yeah, you're right.
- 米奇和默里 - 你说的对
That's right. How are you?
没错 你还好吗?
I'm fine.
我很好
You mean the board? You mean on the board?
你是说那排行榜上的排名?
Yes. Okay. The board.
对 排行榜
I'm fucked on the board. I can't...
别提那排行榜了 我不能
My mind must be other places, 'cause I can't...
我的脑袋一定去了别处 因为我不能...
What? You can't do what?
什么? 你不能什么?
- I can't close them. - Well, they're old.
- 我完成不了那些生意 - 它们太老了
Look, look at this shit they're giving you. Huh?
看看他们给我的这些垃圾
- Yes, they are old. - They're ancient.
- 没错 是很旧了 - 它们太古老了
"Clear Meadows." This shit's dead.
"克利牧场" 已经完蛋了
- It is dead. - Waste of time.
- 对 - 浪费时间
- Yes. I'm no fucking good. - Hey, fuck that shit, George.
- 我不好 - 嘿 别说了 乔治
You had a bad month. You're a good man.
你是个好人 只是这个月运气不好
- I am? - Yeah, you had a bad streak.
- 是吗? - 你运气不太好
Look at this. 15 units, Mountain View, the fucking things get stolen.
看看这个十五个单位 能看见山景 被人偷走了
- He said he filed... - He filed the big one.
- 他说他处理好了 - 他只处理好了那些大生意
He filed the guy from the bar that I closed last night.
他只放好了我昨晚那笔生意
All the little ones, I got to go back.
我得重头再做那些小笔生意
Can you believe this? I got to go back and close again.
你能相信吗? 我得从头来过
I mean, talk about a fucking beat
我是说 我又得去和
that would sap anyone's... wait, wait, wait. Where are the phones?
那些无赖打交道... 等等 电话去了哪里?
- They stole... - They stole...?
- 被偷走了... - 被偷走了?
- What kind of an outfit is it... - They stole the phones.
- 他们干的真彻底... - 他们偷走了电话
...when criminals come and they take... they steal the phones?
那些家伙闯进来偷走了电话!
They stole the leads. They stole the phones,
他们偷走了合约 电话...
they stole... aw, Christ.
他们偷走了...天啊
What am I going to do this month? Shit.
我这个月怎么办?妈的
You think they're going to catch... where are you going?
你觉得警察能抓住... 你要去哪里?
Down the street.
上街去
- Where are you going? - To the... what do you fucking care?
- 你要去哪里? - 去...关你鸟事?
- Aren't you going out today? - With what, John? With what?
- 你今天不是要出去谈生意的吗? - 谈什么 约翰?
Well, answer me. They stole the Glengarry leads.
回答我 他们偷走了那些格兰拉夫的生意单子
- They stole Rio Rancho. - I have stuff from last year's file.
- 他们偷走了尼奥牧场的单子 - 我还有去年的档案
Oh, oh, oh. Your "nostalgia" file.
哦 你的旧档案
Oh, great. That's great, 'cause I don't...
太好了 那我便不需要...
- Do you want to go out today? - I don't have to eat this month.
- 你今天想出去谈生意吗? - 我这个月不用吃饭了
Great. Give them to me.
很好 拿给我
Bring them. Come on.
快点拿给我
Fucking Mitch and Murray are going to shit a...
该死的米奇和默里一定会...
What am I going to do all month?
我这个月该怎么办?
See, the thing of it is,
听着 问题在与
is were the leads insured? You think?
有没有买保险 你怎么看?
- What? - Were the leads insured?
- 什么? - 那些合约有没有买保险?
I don't know, why?
我不知道 为什么?
'Cause if they weren't, I know Mitch and Murray...
如果没买保险的话 我知道米奇和默里.
- What? - They'll be upset.
- 什么? - 他们会很不开心
That's right.
说的对
You're right.
你说的对
He said we're all going to have to talk to the guy.
他说我们全部要录口供
- To... - The cop.
- 要... - 要向那警察录口供
Great. We have to talk to the cop.
很好 我们要录口供
- Another waste of time. - A waste of time? Why?
- 又一次浪费时间 - 浪费时间? 为什么这么说?
Why? 'Cause they're not going to find the guy.
为什么? 因为他们抓不住那家伙的
- The cops? - Yes, the cops. No.
- 警察? - 对 警察不对
The cops aren't going to find the guy?
警察抓不到那家伙?
- Nope. - Why do you think so?
- 对 抓不到 - 为什么这么说?
Why? Because they are stupid. Where were you last night?
因为他们太笨了 你昨晚在什么地方?
- Where were you? - Where was I?
- 你呢? - 我?
- Yeah. - I was at home.
- 对 - 我待在家里
- Where were you? - At home.
- 你昨晚在哪里? - 在家
See? Were you the guy who broke in?
你就是那进来偷东西的家伙吗?
- Was I? - Yes.
- 我? - 对
- No. - Then don't sweat it. You know why?
- 不是 - 那就不用紧张知道为什么吗?
- No. - You have nothing to hide.
- 不知道 - 你没什么要隐瞒的
- When I talk to police, I get nervous. - Yes, you know who doesn't?
- 我对着警察就会紧张 - 你知道谁不会紧张吗?
- No. Who? - Thieves.
- 不知道谁啊? - 那些贼
I don't know what I'm going to tell them.
我不知道该和他说些什么
The truth. Always tell them the truth.
说事实 永远不要说假话
It's the easiest thing to remember.
记住这点就可以了
Whoa, whoa! "Patel"?
柏特?
"Ravidam Patel"?
"莱费顿柏特"?
How am I going to make a living on these deadbeats?
叫我怎么靠这些二溜子维持生计?
- Where did you get this from, a morgue? - Look, I'm...
- 你从哪里找来的 太平间? - 听着 我...
Come on. What's the point? What's the fucking point?
得了你这算什么意思?
I got to argue with you, I got to knock heads with the cops,
我得和你争吵 得应付警察
I'm busting my balls to sell your dirt
我尽心尽力为你办事
to deadbeats... money in the mattress.
替你卖东西给那些二溜子
I come back, you can't even keep the contracts safe.
但你连合约也保管不好
I got to go out... fuck this shit.
我要出去 去他妈的
I'm going to go out and re-close last week's stuff.
我要出去重新完成上周的生意
No, the word from Murray is leave them alone.
不 默里说先别理它们
If he needs a new sig, he'll go out himself.
如果有需要的话 他回来后会亲自去处理的
- Murray's gonna go out? - He'll be "president of the company
- 默里去了外地? - 他回来后就会成为
just in from out of town," all right?
这公司的新总裁
Okay, okay, okay. Give me this shit.
好吧 给我那些垃圾
- I'm giving you three leads. - Three? I count two.
- 我给你三单生意 - 三单? 只有两单啊
- There's three leads there. - Patel? Fuck you.
- 有三单 - 算上柏特那单? 去你的
Fucking Shiva handed this guy a million dollars,
就是老天给这家伙一百万
told him, "Sign the deal," he wouldn't sign.
叫他在合约上签字 他也不会签的
And the god Vishnu, too, into the bargain. Fuck you.
换了毗瑟拿也一样 去你妈的
You know your business, I know mine. Your business is being an asshole.
你知道你做的事我也知道我的工作 你所做的事令人讨厌
If I find out whose fucking cousin you are, I'm gonna go to him
如果给我知道谁是你的表兄 我会去告诉他
and figure out a way to have your ass... fuck you!
让他教训你一顿...去你的!
I'm waiting for the new leads.
我就在这里等新的生意
Get the chalk! Hey! Get the chalk!
快拿粉笔来!
Get the... I did it... I closed 'em.
我成功了 我完成那些生意
I closed the cocksucker. Get the chalk.
快拿粉笔来 我完成了那些垃圾生意
Put me on the board, John. Put me on the Cadillac board!
快把我名字写到销售榜上去 约翰!
Williamson, pick up the fucking chalk.
威林逊 快拿粉笔来
- Rick... eight units, Mountain View. - You sold eight Mountain View?
- 山景阁八个单位 - 你卖出了八个单位?
You bet your ass! Who wants to go to lunch?
没错! 谁想去吃午饭?
Who wants to go to lunch... I'm buying.
谁想去吃午饭?我请客
Williamson... $82,000, 12 grand in my commission.
威林逊 八万两千美元 一万二佣金
On deadbeat magazine subscription leads.
那些杂志社的混蛋买的
- Who? - Bruce and Harriett Nyborg.
- 谁? - 布鲁斯和哈瑞特
Read it. What the hell happened here?
这里发生什么事了?
Fuck! I had them on River Glen.
去他妈的!
- What happened? - Somebody broke in.
- 发生什么事了? - 有人闯进了办公室
- Eight units! - Yeah.
- 八个单位! - 对
- Shelly! - Big deal... I broke a bad streak.
- 沙利! - 一笔大生意...我不再走霉运了
Shelly "The Machine" Levene. That's great.
沙利赖芬 "销售机器" 太棒了
Thank you, George. Hey...
谢谢 乔治 嘿...
- grab the phone, call Mitch. - They took the phones.
- 打电话给米奇 - 他们偷走了电话
They took the leads, the cash, the contracts.
他们偷走了单子 现金还有合约
- We had a robbery. - When?
- 我们被劫了 - 什么时候的事?
- Last night, this morning. - They took the leads?
- 昨晚 今早 - 他们拿走了生意单子?
Fucking asshole.
他妈的王八蛋
What? They beat you with a rubber bat?
怎么了?他们有用橡胶棒打你?
Cop couldn't find his dick with two hands and a map.
警察光靠双手和地图是抓不到罪犯的
Anybody who talks to this asshole is a fucking asshole.
谁和这王八蛋说话便也是王八蛋
- You gonna turn state's? - Fuck you, Ricky.
- 你要造反吗? - 去你的 理查德
I ain't going out today. I'm going home.
我今天不出去谈生意了 我要回家去
I'm going home because nothing's accomplished here.
因为待在这里只会一事无成
- Anybody talks to this guy... - Guess what "The Machine" did.
- 谁和那家伙说话... - 猜猜"销售机器"做了什么
- Fuck "The Machine." - Mountain View, eight units.
- 去他妈的"机器" - 八个山景阁单位
Cop's got no right to talk to me that way. I did not rob the place.
警察没权利对我那样说话 又不是我干的
- Did you hear what I said? - Yeah, he closed the deal.
- 你听见我说什么了吗? - 听到了 他完成了那些生意
Eight units, Mountain View.
八个山景阁单位
- You did that? - Yeah.
- 你成功了? - 对
- Fuck you. - Guess who?
- 去你妈的 - 猜猜谁是买家?
- When? - Just now.
- 什么时候? - 刚刚
- Guess who? - You just... this morning?
- 猜猜谁是买家? - 你今早刚谈成?
Harriett and blah blah Nyborg.
哈瑞特和黎波
- You did that? - Yeah... $82,000.
- 你卖出去了? - 对 八万两千块
- Those fucking deadbeats. - My ass. I told 'em... listen to this.
- 那些该死的混帐 - 我告诉他们...听着
- I don't want to hear your war stories. - Fuck you, Dave.
- 我不想听你的破故事 - 去你的 戴夫
I said, "You have to believe in yourself."
我说 "你要相信自己"
Give me a lead. I'm going out. I'm getting out.
给我单生意 我要出去谈生意
- Fuck the leads. I'm going home. - Fuck me, Bruce.
- 去他妈的生意 我要回家 - 去他妈的 布鲁斯
- You have to believe in yourself. - We haven't got a lead.
- 你得相信自己 - 我们没有生意可谈
- Why not? - They took 'em.
- 为什么? - 都被偷走了
They're fucking garbage, any case. The whole goddamn...
反正那些也都是垃圾生意
"You look around, you say, 'This one has so-and-so. I got nothing.
看看周围的人 那人有这个有那个 我什么都没有
But why? Why don't I get the opportunities?"'
为什么我就没有机会呢?
- Did they steal the contracts? - What the fuck do you care?
- 他们偷了合约吗? - 你关心这个干吗?
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
你这话什么意思?
Will you shut up? I'm telling him something.
你闭嘴好吗? 我正在和他谈事情
Could we get some coffee?
有人要喝咖啡吗?
- How are you doing? - Fine.
- 你没事吧? - 我很好
Anybody's going out, I could use some coffee.
有人出去就买些咖啡回来
- "You do get the opportunity." - Fuck is that supposed to mean?
- "你现在就有个好机会" - 那是什么意思?
"You do get the opportunities. You get 'em as I get 'em,
你有机会的 你有机会 我也有机会
- as everybody gets 'em." - I don't care they stole the contracts?
- 人人都有机会的 - 我不在乎他们偷走了合约?
I got 'em in the kitchen, eating their crumb cake...
我在厨房内一边吃蛋糕一边说服他们
- What does that mean? - It means, Dave,
- 你那话是什么意思? - 戴夫 我是说
You haven't closed a good one in a month.
你一整个月都没完成一单生意
None of my business, you want to push me to answer you.
不关我的事 是你逼我说的
So you haven't got a contract to get stolen and so forth.
所以你根本没合约给人偷
You got a mean streak in you. Shut the fuck up!
你的性情真坏 都给我闭嘴!
Ricky, you got a mean streak in you, and what are you babbling about?
理查德 你这个性情真坏 你在胡说些什么?
You bring that shit up... on my volume?
你在谈论我的销售额吗?
If you were on a bad one and I brought it up to you, you'd harbor it.
如果现在是我在嘲笑你
You'd harbor it a long while and you'd be right.
你一定会一直怀恨在心
- Who said "Fuck 'The Machine"'? - Fuck "The Machine"?
- 是谁说"去他妈的机器"? - 去他妈的"机器"?
Fuck "The Machine"? Fuck "The Machine"!
去他妈的"机器"? 去他妈的"机器"!
What is this, courtesy class? You're fucked, Rick.
你是在给我上礼仪课吗? 去你妈的
Are you fucking nuts? You're hot, so you think
你发疯了吗? 你很红 所以你就以为
- you're the ruler of this place. - Wait a minute, Dave.
- 你可以指手划脚了吗? - 等等 戴夫
- Shut up! - Okay...
- 闭嘴! - 好吧...
You want to decide who should be dealt with how, is that it?
你想决定谁该干什么 对吗?
I come into the office today, I get humiliated by some jag-off cop.
今天我一走进办公室 就被那些笨蛋警察羞辱
I get accused of...
我被指为...
I get shit thrown in my face because you're top name on the board?
我被你侮辱就因为你的销售额最高?
Is that what I did, Dave... I humiliated you?
我有侮辱你吗 戴夫?
- Oh, my God, I'm sorry. - Sitting on top of the world.
- 天啊 对不起 - 你高高在上
Sitting on top of the world... everything's fucking peach fuzz.
坐在世界的最顶端... 一切都不再受到尊重
I don't get a moment to spare for some bust-out humanitarian
我没那么有空 花时间去侮辱
- down on his luck lately? - Fuck you!
- 那些没用的家伙! - 去你的!
Fuck you, Dave... you know you got a big mouth.
去你的 戴夫... 你知道你很爱炫耀
You make a close, this whole place stinks with your farts for a week...
做成一单生意 你的屁便在这里臭足一星期
how much you just ingested. Oh, what a big man you are!
你赚到多少? 你真伟大!
"Let me buy you a pack of gum... I'll show you how to chew it."
"我来教你该怎么嚼口香糖"
Your pal closes, and all that comes out of your mouth is bile.
你的朋友成功了 你只会乱吠
How fucked-up you are!
你真混!
Who's my pal, Ricky? Hmm? And what are you?
谁是我的好朋友 理查德? 那你呢?
What are you, huh, Bishop Sheen?
你是什么 "主教大人"?
What the fuck are you, "Mr. Slick"?
你他妈的是什么 "滑头"?
What the fuck are you, "Friend to the working man"?
还是"一个职员的好朋友"
Big deal! Fuck you!
去你妈的!
You got the memory of a fucking fly!
你就像只讨厌的苍蝇!
I never liked you, anyway.
我从没喜欢过你
What is this, your farewell speech?
这算什么 你的道别演说?
- I'm going home. - Your farewell to the troops?
- 我要回家去 - 你要离开我们?
I'm not going home. I'm going to Wisconsin.
我不回家 我要去威斯康星
- Have a good trip. - Aw, fuck you!
- 祝你旅途愉快 - 去你的!
Fuck the lot of you! Fuck you all!
去你们的!
You were saying?
你说到哪里了?
Come on.
继续说吧
Come on... you got 'em in the kitchen,
继续吧 你在厨房说服了他们
you're in your shirtsleeves,
你穿着长袖衬衫
you got the stats spread out,
你能闻到
you can smell it. Come on, snap out of it.
一股银纸气味 继续说下去
- You're eating her crumb cake. - Oh yeah, I'm eating her crumb cake.
- 你在吃她的蛋糕 - 对 没错
- How was it? - From the store.
- 味道如何? - 从商店里买来的
- Fuck her. - "Bruce, Harriett...
- 去她妈的 - 布鲁斯 哈瑞特...
we have to admit to ourselves that we see that opportunity
我们要承认我们看见了这机会
and take it... and that's it." Now, we just sit there.
要把握住它 就这样 我们就坐在那里
- I got my pen out. - "Always Be Closing."
- 我拿出笔 - "永远做个成功者"
God, that's what I've been saying... the old ways.
我正是不断这样说的
Convert that motherfucker, sell him, make him sign the check.
给那混蛋洗脑 让他签了支票
They got their money in government bonds...
他们买了很多政府债券
I said, "Fuck it... let's go all the way, the whole route."
我说 "去他妈的债券 全投进去"
I take it and plat it out... eight units, 82 grand, and I say to them,
我划了八个单位 八万两千块 我对他们说
"This is now. This is that thing that you have been dreaming of.
现在就是你们一直梦想的时刻了
You are going to find the suitcase on the train.
你会在火车上找到个行李箱
The man walks in the room, that bag is filled with money.
里面装满了钞票
Harriett, this is it, and Bruce... I don't want to fuck around with you.
哈瑞特和布鲁丝... 我不想愚弄你们
No, I don't. I don't want to pussyfoot around.
我不想四处招摇撞骗
You think you got to look back on this thing? I do, too.
你还要再考虑考虑? 我也要考虑一下
Now, I'm here to do good for you and me... the both of us.
我们大家都有好处
What is the point of some interim position?
先付点订金是什么意思?
The only arrangement I will accept is full investment.
我只接受全额付款
And I mean it, that's it... all eight units. Period."
我是认真的 八个单位一次付清
Now I got the pen in my hand, Rick... hey.
我手上拿着笔 理查德...嘿
I turned that contract around... that's eight units, 82 grand...
我拿着价值八万两千块的合约
and I said, "I want you to sign."
我说 "我要你签了它"
I sat there five minutes.
我坐了五分钟
Then I sat 22 minutes by that kitchen clock on the wall.
跟着在厨房的钟旁做了二十分钟
Ricky... not a word, not a motion.
理查德...面无表情 一言不发
And what am I thinking? "Is my arm getting tired?"
我在想什么? "我的手臂累了吗?"
No. I did it. Just like the old days,
不是 我成功了 就象以前那样
like I used to, like I was taught.
象我被教的那样
- I did it. - Like you taught me.
- 我成功了 - 像你教我的一样
Nobody ever... well, if I did, I'm glad.
从没有人... 若我成功了我很开心
No, what I did... I locked on 'em.
我只是紧紧的盯着他们
I locked all on them... nothing on me... on them.
我紧紧的盯着他们 面无表情
And, oh God, I am holding my last thought,
天啊 我拿定了主意
"Now is the time."
"现在是时候了"
They signed. It was great.
他们签了合约 太棒了
It was so fucking great.
真他妈的太棒了
It was like they wilted all at once.
他们一下子意志消沉下来
No gesture, nothing... just together.
没有做手势 只是靠在一起
Honest to God, they both imperceptibly slumped.
他们俩异常的意志消沉
And then he reached and he took the pen and he signed,
然后他伸手拿笔签了和约
passed it to her and she signed.
然后递给她 她也签了名
It was solemn... fucking solemn.
那场面太严肃了
I let it sit, and then I nodded. I said, "Harriett, Bruce,"
我没迫他们 接着我点了点头 我说"哈瑞特 布鲁斯"
then I pointed into the living room to the sideboard.
我指向客厅餐具柜那里
I didn't know there was a sideboard in there.
我不知道那里有餐具柜
He went over, he brought us back a drink...
他走过去 倒了杯酒给我们
little shot glasses with a pretty design in 'em.
用很细很精致的那种
And we just toasted in silence.
我们默默的干杯
Great sale, Shelly.
做的好 沙利
Great.
太好了
Fuck! Send me out! Give me leads!
他妈的!快给我新的生意! 我要出门!
Williamson! Send me out!
威林逊 快派我出去!
- The leads are coming. - Get 'em to me.
- 生意马上就到 - 快给我
I talked to Mitch and Murray an hour ago. They're coming in.
我一小时前和米奇还有默里谈过 他们正赶来这里
- They're a bit upset over this. - Did you tell 'em my sale?
- 他们对此有点不开心 - 有告诉他们我做成了生意吗?
How could I tell 'em your sale? I didn't have a tele...
我怎告诉他们你做成了生意? 我连电话都没有...
I'll tell 'em your sale when they bring in the leads.
他们来时我会告诉他们的
We had a little... you closed the deal, you made a good sale. Fine.
你完成了生意 你做的很好
- Better than a good sale. - I have a lot of things on my mind.
- 不止是笔好生意 - 我很忙
They're coming and they're very upset. I'm trying to make...
他们正赶来这里 而且很不开心 我正试着...
All I'm telling you is, you can tell them it was a remarkably good sale.
我只想你告诉他们 这是笔有纪念价值的好生意
The only thing remarkable about it is who you made it to.
唯一值得注意的 是你做成生意的对象
- What the fuck does that mean? - If the sale sticks it'll be a miracle.
- 这话什么意思? - 如果交易成功那将是个奇迹
"If the sale sticks"? Why shouldn't the sale stick?
如果成功的话? 为什么不会成功?
Oh, fuck you! You do not know your job.
去你的! 你不知道你该做什么
Do you know that? A man is his job!
你知道吗? 要知人善用!
You are fucked at yours. You hear what I'm saying to you?
你却自以为是 你听到我在说什么吗?
Your "End of the Month" fucking boar...
你那该死的销售榜...
you do not know how to run this office.
你不懂如何管理这办公室
You haven't got the sense. You haven't got the balls.
你没有头脑 根本不是男人
Have you ever been on a sit? Has this cocksucker been on a sit?
你有成功过吗?这衰人有吗?
- Did you ever sit... - If I were you, I would calm down.
- 你有做成过... - 如果我是你 我会冷静下来
Would you? What are you gonna do, fire me?
是吗? 你想对我怎样 开除我?
Oh, oh, Rick, ooh.
哦 理查德
- It's not impossible. - Really? On an $80,000 day?
- 那不是没可能 - 真的吗? 我一天赚了八万块
- It's not even noon yet. - You closed 'em today?
- 甚至还没到下午呢 - 你今天做成这单生意了?
I got up early this morning, tracked 'em down, and closed it.
我一早便起来找他们 做成了这单生意
What I'm saying to you is that things change.
我要告诉你一切都改变了
That's where you fuck up. You don't know. You can't look back.
这正是你失败之处 你不能回头看
You don't see who's coming. Maybe it's someone new, huh?
你看不到谁在赶上来 或许是个新人?
Maybe it's someone else, but you don't know...
也许是其他人 但你不知道
you can't look back, because you don't know your history!
你不能回头看 因为你不知道自己的过去!
When we were on Rio Rancho, who was the top man, huh?
我们在推销尼奥牧场的时候 谁是最棒的?
For what, two months, three months?
有两个月 或是三个月?
How about eight months, for three years in a row!
三年里有八个月我排第一!
Luck... was that it, John? Or purloined fucking leads?
你要说是我运气好 约翰? 或是靠偷的生意?
- It was talent! - Yes.
- 是才能 - 是的
Door to door. It's called "cold calling," John.
上门挨家挨户推销 这叫"电话推销" 约翰
Shit, I don't even know their name. They don't want to buy what I've got.
我甚至不知道他们叫什么 他们不想买我有的东西
Soft sell... we were doing it before we had a name for it.
劝诱推销 没有这名称前 我们就已经在这样做了
- Am I right? - You're right, you're right.
- 我说的没错吧? - 对
You wouldn't know, you cock... he doesn't even know what a streak is.
你不会知道的... 他甚至连什么是性情也不知道
What the hell are you?
你究竟是谁?
You're a fucking secretary. Fuck you!
你只是个该死的秘书 去你的!
That's my message to you... fuck you, and kiss my ass.
我正要这样说你 去你的 吻我屁股吧
If you don't like that, I go across the street and speak to Jerry Graff.
你不喜欢的话 我就去隔壁街找谢利格拉夫
Period. Fuck you.
去你妈的
Listen to me... you put me on that fucking board,
听我说...把我的名字写上销售榜
and I want three promising leads for today,
我今天要三单有希望的生意
I don't want any bullshit, and I want 'em close together,
我不要那些垃圾 最好是靠的比较近的生意
because I am going to close them all.
因为我要一次过完成它们
And that's all I have to say to you.
就这么多 我说完了
He's right, Williamson.
他说的对 威林逊
I'm sorry, but it's wrong, and you know whose fault it is?
对不起 但这样做是错的 你知道是谁的错吗?
Mitch and Murray.
米奇和默里
To hell with him. Let's get some lunch, huh, Rick?
理查德 一起去吃午饭吧?
The leads won't be up here till later anyway.
反正要迟一点才有生意做
You're a client. I just sold you five waterfront Glengarry Farms.
你来扮客户 我刚卖了五个格兰加利农场给你
I do this with my hair, throw me the cue "Kenilworth."
看见我摸我的头发 就提示我"肯尼维斯"
- Which is it? - Kenilworth.
- 哪里? - 肯尼维斯
I own the property. My mother owns the property.
我在那里拥有物业 其实是我妈的
I put her into it.
我说服了她
You look on the plats when you go home. You'll see...
回家后可以看看地图 你会发现
A-3 through 10, 26 through 30.
A-3到10 26到30
- Take your time. If you still feel... - I won't need more time, Rick.
- 你可再考虑一下 如果你... - 不用了 理查德
- I've bought a lot of property. - I've got to talk to you.
- 我已经有很多物业了 - 我要和你谈谈
Jim, what are you doing here?
吉姆 你来这里干什么?
Jim Lingk, D. Ray Morton.
吉姆林克 瑞莫顿
- I'm glad to meet you. - I put Jim into Black Creek.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我刚卖了黑溪的物业给他
- Are you acquainted with... - Black Creek? No.
- 你知道... - 黑溪? 我不知道
- Ooh, in Florida! - Yes.
- 哦 是在佛罗里达! - 对
- I meant to speak to you about that. - We'll do that this weekend.
- 我喜欢谈这个 - 周末再谈吧
My wife suggested I look into it.
我太太叫我留意那地方
Beautiful rolling land... I was telling Jim and Jinny.
那地方很漂亮 我有告诉吉姆和珍尼
Ray, I got to tell you something. You eat in a lot of restaurants?
瑞 我有事要告诉你 你去过很多餐厅品尝美味对吗?
I know you do. Ray is with American Express.
我知道你有 瑞在美国运通银行工作
- Can I tell Jim what you do? - Sure.
- 我能告诉吉姆你的职业吗? - 当然可以
Ray is the director of all European sales and services...
瑞主管所有的欧洲买卖和服务
what I'm saying is, you haven't had a meal until you've tasted...
我要说的是 你没尝过美味 除非你吃过
I was at the Lingks'...
我有一次在林克家里
what was that service feature you were talking about?
你说的那种特色服务叫什么?
- Which... - "Home cooking."
- 那个... - "家常饭"
- You had a tag phrase you used? - "Cooking"...
- 有个特别的叫法? - "烹调"
"Home cook..." the monthly interview.
"家庭烹调..." 那个每月一次的访问
- The magazine! - Yes.
- 那杂志! - 对!
Is that something I can talk about?
能谈谈吗?
It won't be out until the February issue, but go ahead.
要到二月份的杂志才会登出来 不过没关系 你说吧
- Are you sure? - Go ahead.
- 你确定吗? - 说吧
Ray was eating at one of his company men's homes in France.
瑞在法国 去手下家里吃饭
- The man is French? - No, but his wife is.
- 是个法国人? - 不是 他太太才是
His wife.
他太太
Ray, what time do you have?
瑞 现在几点了?
- 12:15. - I got to get you on the plane.
- 12点15分 - 我得送你去机场了
- Didn't I say the 2:00? - No, the 1:00.
- 我不是说两点吗? - 不 是一点
Remember the 1:00... that's why we couldn't talk till Kenilworth.
所以要到肯尼维斯才能继续谈
You're right, the 1:00... let's scoot.
你说的没错 一点钟 我们走吧
- A pleasure. - I got to talk to you.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我有话要跟你说
I got to run Ray to the airport. Let's hustle... John!
我要送瑞去机场 迟些再谈...约翰!
Get on the phone to Pittsburgh, American Express there, for Mr. Morton.
打电话去匹兹堡的美国运通
Tell them he's on the 1:00. I'll see you.
告诉他们瑞先生坐一点的飞机 再见
Christ, I'm sorry you came all the way in.
对不起要你白跑一趟
I'm running Ray to the airport. You wait here and...
我要送瑞去机场 你可以在这里等
no, I can't. I'm meeting your man at the bank.
不行 我要和那人一去走了
I wish you'd have phoned! Are you and Jinny going to be home?
你该先打电话来的! 你们今晚会在家吗?
- I don't know. - Rick?
- 我不知道 - 理查德?
- What? - Kenilworth?
- 什么事? - 肯尼维斯?
- I'm sorry? - Kenilworth.
- 你说什么? - 肯尼维斯
Oh, God. Excuse me, Ray... just a minute.
对不起 瑞 等我一下
Jim, I told you who he is... the senior vice-president of American Express.
我告诉过你他是谁... 美国运通银行的高级副总裁
His family owns 32 per...
他的家族拥有32%...
over the past years, I have sold him... I can't tell you the dollar amount...
过去几年 我卖给他很多土地... 我说不出准确的数字
but quite a lot of land.
很多块土地
I promised him five weeks ago that I would go to the wife's birthday party
我五星期前答应参加他太太今晚
in Kenilworth tonight. I have to go, you understand?
在肯尼维斯的生日派对 我一定得去参加 明白吗?
They treat me like a member of the family. I have to go.
他们对我就象对自己家人那样
It's funny... you get a picture of the corporation-type company man,
真有趣...你知道他们那些家伙
all business... this guy, I'll tell you.
只知道谈生意... 这人 我以后再告诉你
We'll go to his house someday.
我们找个日子去他家
Let me see. Tomorrow. I'm in L.A.?
我看看 明天 我会在洛杉机?
Ah, Monday.
啊 星期一
I'll take you to lunch. Where would you like to eat?
我会找你吃午饭 想去哪里吃?
- My wife... - Rick?
- 我太太... - 理查德?
I can't talk now, Jim... I'll call you tonight. Coming, Ray.
现在我没空 晚上打电话给你 我来了 瑞
My wife said I have to cancel the deal.
我太太说我必须取消那买卖
That's a common reaction, Jim, and let me tell you what it is.
这是正常的反应
That's why you married her. One of the reasons is prudence.
这正是你娶她的原因 她做事谨慎
No, it's a sizable investment. One thinks twice.
这样大的投资是要谨慎的想清楚
It's also something women have. Reaction to the size of the investment.
女人见到这样大的投资是会这样的
Monday, you invite me to dinner again...
星期一你请我吃晚饭
- This woman can cook. - I'm sure she can.
- 他太太手艺很不错 - 我相信
We are going to talk. I want to tell you something.
我们到时再谈 我要告诉你些事情
Something about your acreage I want you to know.
关于你那块地的面积的事 我想你该知道
I can't talk about it here, I really shouldn't, and by law...
现在我不能和你谈 我真的不该告诉你 从法律上说
the man next to you... bought his lot at 42...
排在你后面的那位
phoned to say he already had an offer.
打电话来说他早就预定了
- Rick. - I'm coming.
- 理查德 -  我来了
Ray, what a day. I'll call you this evening.
瑞 真不巧 我晚上会打电话给你
I'm sorry you had to come all the way in. Monday lunch.
很抱歉让你白跑一趟 星期一一起吃午饭
- We have to go. - Monday!
- 我们得走了 - 星期一!
She called the consumer... the attorney general?
她找过司法部长
- They said we have three days. - Who'd she call?
- 他们说我们有三天时间 - 她找了谁?
The attorney ge... it was some consumer office.
司法部长...某个消费者办事处
Why'd she do that, Jim?
她为什么这样做 吉姆?
I don't know.
我不知道
But they said we have three days.
但他们说我们只有三天时间
They said we got three days, yeah.
有三天时间?
Three days?
三天?
- To... you know. - No, I don't know.
- 你知道 去... - 不 我不知道
- Tell me. - To change our minds.
- 告诉我 - 去改变主意 取消合约
Of course you have... three days.
当然你们有三天时间
So we can't talk Monday.
所以等不到星期一再谈
Monday... you saw my book.
星期一...你看到我的时间表了
Jim, Jim... I can't.
吉姆 我没时间
You saw my book. I can't.
你看到我的时间表了
We have to before Monday to get our money back.
我们要在星期一前取回钱
Three business days, they mean.
他们说三个工作日
- Three business days. - Wednesday, Thursday, Friday.
- 三个工作日 - 星期三 星期四 星期五
- I don't understand. - That's what they are, three business...
- 我不明白 - 三个工作日
if we wait till Monday, my time limit runs out.
若等到星期一那就来不及了
- You don't count Saturday. - I'm not.
- 你没算上星期六 - 没有
I'm saying you don't include Saturday in the three days.
我是说你没把星期六算在内
- It's not a business day. - I am not counting it.
- 那不是工作日 - 我没算在里面
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday... so it would have elapsed.
星期三 星期四 星期五 然后就会过期了
What would have elapsed?
什么会过期?
If we wait till Monday it would have elapsed!
如果我们等到星期一就来不及了!
- When did you write the check? - Yesterday.
- 你什么时候签的支票? - 昨天
- What was yesterday? - Tuesday.
- 昨天星期几? - 星期二
- And when was that check cashed? - I don't know.
- 支票什么时候兑现的? - 我不知道
What was the earliest it could have been cashed?
最早可能是什么时候?
- I don't know. - Today.
- 我不知道 - 今天
Today. Which, in any case, it was not...
今天 而且
there was something on the agreement I wanted to go over with you.
我还有些细节想和你谈谈
It wasn't cashed?
还没有兑现吗?
I just phoned downtown... it's on their desk.
我刚打电话去问 还在办公桌上
- Rick. - One moment.
- 理查德 - 再等我一会
One point, in fact, of which I spoke to you of which,
我要对你说的是
I can't talk to you about it here.
我现在不能和你谈
- Levene! - Listen to me.
- 赖芬! - 听我说
The statute is for your protection. I have no complaint with that.
法例保障你的利益 我没有意见
In fact, I was a member of the board when we drafted it.
事实上 我也是 草拟那法案的成员之一
So quite the opposite. It says,
法例说
"You can change your mind three 'working days'
你可在买卖成交后
from the time the deal was closed."
三个工作日内改变主意
- Levene! - Wait a second!
- 赖芬! - 等一下!
Which is not until the check is cashed!
而不是支票兑现后!
I'm through with this "meshugaas." Nobody should talk to a man that way.
我受够这蠢货了 没人能那样跟我说话
- How are you talking to me that way? - Levene!
- 你怎么能那样跟我说话? - 赖芬!
- How can you talk to me that way? - I'm gonna flag a cab.
- 怎能那样跟我说话? - 我去叫的士
- I didn't rob... - Shelly, get in the office.
- 我没有打劫... - 沙利 进办公室来
"Where were you last?" Is anybody listening to me?
"你昨晚在哪里?" 有人在听我说吗?
- Where's Moss? - Is this Levene?
- 莫斯在哪里? - 这人是赖芬?
Perhaps I could assist you. Excuse us, will you?
也许我可帮你应付他 失陪了
I work here! I didn't come in here to be mistreated!
我是来这里工作的! 我不是来受虐待的!
- Go to lunch, will you? - That's why I came in to work today.
- 去吃午饭 好吗? - 那正是我今天来工作的原因
The leads come in, I'll let you know.
有生意来我会告诉你的
- That's why I came in! - Just go to lunch.
- 我就是为此来这里的! - 去吃饭吧
- I don't wanna go to lunch! - Go to lunch, George.
- 我不想去吃午饭! - 吃午饭去 乔治
Where does he get off talking that way to a working man?
怎么能容忍他这样对人说话? 我是来工作的
Take it outside. We have people trying to do business.
出去再说吧 有人还在做生意
That's what I came in here for. That's what I'm trying to do!
所以我来这里 我试着做成生意!
- I meet Gestapo tactics. - Excuse me.
- 我碰上了盖世太保 - 对不起
I meet Gestapo tactics!
有人用盖世太保那套对付我!
I meet Gestapo tactics. That's not right.
我碰上了盖世太保! 那是不对的
No man has the right... no man has the right...
没人有权利...
"Call an attorney"... that means you're under...
"找律师"...这代表你被捕了
he says, "Cooperate or we'll take you downtown."
他说 "不合作就送你去商业区"
That's not... as long as I've...
只要我还没死就不能忍受...
Will you get out of here?
你离开这里好吗?
Will you get out of here? Will you?
请你出去好吗?
I'm trying to run an office here. Now, will you go to lunch?
我在管理这办公室 现在 你去吃午饭好吗?
Go to lunch. Will you go to lunch?
去吃午饭好吗?
- Excuse me. - Where did Moss...?
- 对不起 - 莫斯呢?
- Excuse me, please? - Did he go to the restaurant?
- 失陪了 - 他去饭店了吗?
Will you excuse me, please?
别打扰我们 好吗?
I'm sorry, I...
我很抱歉 我...
I apologize to you. It's...
我向你道歉
It's not me, it's my wife.
其实是我太太
What is it?
怎么了?
- I told you. - Tell me again.
- 我告诉你了 - 再告诉我一遍
- What's going on here? - Tell me again... your wife?
- 这么出什么事了? - 再告诉我 你太太怎么了?
- I told you. - Tell me again.
- 我说过了 - 再说一遍吧
She wants her money back.
她想要回那笔钱
We're gonna speak to her.
我们和她谈谈
No, she told me, "Right now."
不用了 她和我说 "马上把钱拿回来"
- We're gonna speak to her, Jim. - She won't listen.
- 我们和她谈谈 吉姆 - 她不会听的
- She... - Roma!
- 她... - 诺马!
She said if don't get my money back, to call the state's attorney.
她说拿不回钱 就去找州政府律师
No. No. This is something she said.
不 不 她只是那么说而已
- We don't have to do that. - She told me I have to.
- 我们不需要那样做 - 她说我一定要拿回钱
- No, Jim. - I do.
- 不 吉姆 - 我一定得拿回钱
Listen, I do... if I don't get my money back...
听着... 如果我拿不回我的钱
Roma, I'm talking to you.
诺马 我在和你说话
Listen... will someone get this guy off my back, please?
有人能替我应付一下吗?
- You have a problem? - Yes, I have a problem!
- 你有问题? - 对 我也有问题!
Yes, I do, my friend. It is not me
我也有问题 朋友 现在不是我
that ripped the joint off. I'm doing business.
在办公室里捣乱 我在谈生意
I will be with you in a while, got it?
一会儿再和你谈 好吗?
Where are you going? Where are you going?
你要去哪里?
This is me!
是我!
Jim, this is Ricky, Jim.
吉姆 是我 理查德
Jim, anything you want, you want it, you got it.
你想要什么都行
Understand? This is me.
明白吗? 是我
Something upset you.
有事情困扰你?
Yes. Sit down now.
那就坐下
Sit down. You tell me what it is,
坐下 你告诉我是什么困扰你
am I gonna help you fix it?
我会不会帮你解决?
You're goddamned right I am.
我会帮你解决的
Sit down.
坐下
I'll tell you something,
我告诉你
sometimes we need someone from outside.
有时我们需要一个局外人
Sit. Talk to me, come on.
坐 告诉我 说吧
I can't negotiate.
我不能谈判
What does that mean?
那是什么意思?
What?
什么?
What? Say the words.
什么?说啊
I don't have the power.
我没勇气
Okay, I said it.
我说出来了
- What power? - To negotiate.
- 什么勇气? - 谈判的勇气
To negotiate what?
谈判什么?
This.
这事
- What this? - The deal.
- 什么事? - 那买卖
The deal?
买卖?
Forget the deal, Jim.
忘掉那买卖 吉姆
You got something on your mind, what is it?
还有别的事 究竟是什么事?
What?
是什么?
I can't talk to you.
我不能和你说
You met my wife.
你见过我太太
What?
怎么了?
I met your wife, what?
我见过 那又怎样?
What, Jim?
是什么 吉姆?
Come on, let's go. Let's go, let's go.
走吧
Get a drink, come on.
出去喝一杯
No, no, she told me not to talk to you.
不 她叫我别和你谈
Come on, we're gonna go around the corner.
我们去角落的酒吧
We'll have a drink. Who's gonna know?
喝酒而已 谁会知道?
She told me to get the check back, otherwise...
她说我得拿回支票 不然...
Forget the deal, Jimmy. Forget the deal.
忘掉那交易
The deal is dead. You know me, the deal's dead.
那交易已经玩完了 你知道的
Am I talking about the deal?
我有提那交易吗?
That's over.
那已经结束了
Please... let's talk about you.
现在谈谈你的事
I'm gonna tell you something.
我告诉你
Your life is your own.
你的生活属于你自己的
You have a contract with your wife,
你和你太太结了婚
you have certain things you do jointly,
你们一起做某些事情
you have a bond there. And there are other things,
你们有约束 但还有别的东西
and those things are yours. You needn't feel ashamed.
那些是你的 你不需要觉得惭愧
You needn't feel that you're being untrue
不需要觉得不忠
or that she would abandon you if she knew.
或是担心她知道后会遗弃你
This is your life.
这是你的生活
Yes?
明白吗?
Now, I want to talk to you because you're obviously upset,
我想和你谈是因为你不开心
and that concerns me.
那让我很担心
Let's go, come on, right now.
走吧
Let's go, come on.
我们走吧
Roma.
诺马
- What? - The check, it's...
- 什么事? - 支票...
What did I tell you?
我怎么和你说的?
No, what did I tell you about the three days?
关于那三天期限我怎么说的?
Roma, would you? I'd like to get some lunch.
诺马 你有空吗? 你能帮我买些午饭吗?
I am talking with Mr. Lingk, if you please.
我正在和林克先生谈事情
I will be with you in a while. Just check with Mr. Williamson.
我一会儿就来 找威林逊吧
- People downtown said... - Call them again. Mr. Williamson!
- 商业区的人说... - 再打电话给他们 威林逊!
Yes?
什么事?
Mr. Lingk and I are going to go to the...
林克先生和我要去...
Oh, yes, please. The police can be...
是的 警察能...
- What are the police doing here? - It's nothing.
- 警察来这里干吗? - 没什么
- What are the police doing here? - We had a slight burglary last night.
- 警察来这里干吗? - 昨晚有人入室行窃
It's nothing, I was just assuring Mr. Lingk.
没什么大不了的 我正在令他放心
Mr. Lingk? James Lingk? Your contract went out.
林克先生?詹姆士林克? 你的合约办妥了
- Nothing to worry about. - John, John...
- 不用担心 - 约翰 约翰...
- Your contract went out to the bank. - You cashed my check?
- 你的合约存放在银行了 - 你兑现了我的支票?
- Mr. Williamson... - The check was cashed.
- 威林逊先生... - 支票兑现了
The contract was filed and deposited in the bank,
合约存放在银行里了
and we're completely insured in any case, as you know.
由我们来承保
- You cashed the check? - Not to my knowledge, no.
- 你兑现了支票? - 我不知道
- Though I'm sure we can... - Not to my knowledge.
- 我们可以... - 我什么都不知道
Christ! I... Oh, Christ.
天啊!我... 天啊
Don't follow me, just don't follow me, okay?
别跟着我 好吗?
I've let you down. I know I've let you down.
我知道我令你失望
I'm sorry, forgive me. I-I...
我很抱歉 请原谅我
I don't... I don't know anymore.
我什么都不知道了
I... forgive me.
我...原谅我
You stupid fucking cunt.
你这笨蛋
You, Williamson, I'm talking to you, shithead.
我在对你说话 威林逊
You just cost me $6,000.
你害我损失了六千块
$6,000, and one Cadillac. That's right.
六千块和一辆卡迪拉克
What are you gonna do about it?
你打算怎么办?
What are you gonna do about it, asshole?
你打算怎么补偿我 王八蛋?
You're fucking shit.
他这他妈的没用的东西
Where did you learn your trade,
你在哪里学做生意的
you stupid fucking cunt, you idiot?
你这个傻瓜 蠢货!
Who ever told you that you could work with men?
谁告诉你可以和人一起工作?
Could I...?
我能...?
Oh, I'm gonna have your job, shithead.
我会代替你的位置 笨蛋
I'm going downtown. I'm gonna talk to Mitch and Murray.
我去商业区找米奇和默里谈谈
I'm going to Lemkin! I don't care whose nephew you are,
我要去林佩肯! 我才不管你是谁的侄子
who you know, whose dick you're sucking on,
不管你认识谁 是谁的亲戚
you're going out. I swear to you...
我发誓 你要...
Hey, fella, let's get this done.
嘿 伙计 别再说了
Anyone in this office lives on his wits...
这办公室里的人都靠自己的才智谋生
I'm gonna be with you in a second.
再给我一小会儿
What you're hired for is to help us.
公司请你来是帮我们
Does that seem clear to you?
你清楚吗?
To help us! Not to fuck us up!
来帮我们! 不是来破坏我们的买卖!
To help men who are going out there
来帮那些出去谈生意的人
to try to earn a living, you fairy.
维持生计 你这小仙女
You company man.
你这公司的忠实奴才
I'll tell you something else, I hope you ripped the joint off.
我还要告诉你 我真希望是你把这里弄的一团糟
I can tell our friend here something, might help him to catch you.
我可以告诉他 帮他抓你起来
You wanna learn the first rule
如果你真正的活过一日
you'd know if you ever spent a day in your life?
你就会学到第一条规则
You never open your mouth till you know what the shot is.
没搞清楚事情就别开口说话
You fucking child.
你个弱智儿童
You are a shithead, Williamson.
你真是个笨蛋 威林逊
Can't think on your feet, you ought to keep your mouth closed.
不知道那么多就不要出声
Can you hear me? I'm talking to you.
听到我说的话吗? 我在和你说话
Yes, I hear you.
我听到了
Ricky's right. Can't learn in an office, gotta learn it in the street.
理查德说的没错 有些事 在办公室是学不到的 得上街去学
And you sure can't buy it, you gotta live it.
有些东西你没法买到 只能自己去体会
Precisely. Because your partner depends...
完全正确 因为你的拍档需要...
I'm talking to you, trying to tell you something!
我在试着告诉你一些道理!
- You are? - Yeah, I am.
- 是吗? - 是的
- What are you trying to tell me? - What Roma was trying to tell you.
- 你想告诉我什么? - 诺马想告诉你的事情
What I told you a long time ago. You don't belong in this business.
我很早以前就和你说过 你不适合干这行
You might listen to me. One day you could say,
你听我说 有一天你也许会说
"Hey, maybe the guy..." oh, fuck it.
"嘿 也许那人..." 去他妈的
Listen to me now. Your partner depends on you.
现在听好了 你的拍档需要你的帮助
The man who is your partner, depends on you.
你的合伙人依靠着你
You go with him and for him or you're shit!
你要帮他们否则你什么都不是!
You are shit... you can't exist alone.
你是堆狗屎... 你不能独自一人生存
- Excuse me. - "Excuse you," nothing!
- 失陪 - 失陪你个头!
You be as cold as you want. You just fucked a good man
你可真冷酷无情 你刚破坏了一个好人的好事
out of $6,000 and his goddamned bonus
害他不见了六千块还有奖金
because you didn't know the shot.
就因为你不清楚状况
You can do that and you're not man enough to say it gets you?
你做的出却没勇气去面对?
I don't know what... if you can't take something from that,
我不知道... 如果你这样也学不懂的话
then you're... scum! You're fucking white bread.
那你就是人渣! 你他妈的是白痴!
A child would know it, he's right.
连小孩都知道 他说的对
If you're gonna make something up, be sure that it helps.
如果你想帮手 先要肯定是有帮助的
Hmm? Or keep your mouth shut.
不然就闭上你的臭嘴
I'm done with you.
我说完了
How do you know I made it up?
你怎么知道我在撒谎?
What?
什么?
How do you know I made it up?
你怎知道我撒谎?
What are you talking about, huh?
你在说什么?
You said, "Don't make something up unless it's sure to help."
你说"要先肯定有帮助才去做"
- How did you know I made it up? - What are you talking about?
- 你怎知我在撒谎? - 你在说什么?
I told the customer his contract had gone to the bank.
我告诉客户合约已送去银行
Yeah. Well, hadn't it?
对 不是送去了吗?
No, it hadn't.
不 没有送去
Don't fuck with me.
别愚弄我
Don't fuck with me! What are you getting at?
别愚弄我! 你想说什么?
I'm saying this, Shelly...
我是在说 沙利...
usually I take the contracts to the bank,
通常我会拿合约去银行
last night I didn't.
昨晚上则没有
Last night I stayed home with my kids.
我昨晚待在家里和孩子们一起
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的?
One night in a year, I left a contract on my desk.
一年中只有昨晚上 我把合约留在桌上
No one knew that but you.
除了你之外 没有人知道
Now, how did you know that?
你怎么知道的?
You want to talk to me or you want to talk to someone else?
你是要和我说还是想和警察谈谈?
Because this is my job!
这是我的工作!
This is my job on the line and you are gonna talk to me!
这是我的工作 你得告诉我!
Now how did you know that contract was on my desk?
你怎么知道合约在我桌上?
You are so full of shit!
你真的满口废话!
- You robbed the office. - Oh, sure, I robbed the office.
- 是你打劫了办公室 - 没错 是我干的
Oh sure! You asshole.
当然!你个王八蛋
What did you do with the leads?
那些合约单子在哪里?
You wanna go in there? I tell him what I know,
你想进去谈? 我告诉他我知道的
he's gonna dig up something. You got an alibi last night?
他会查出来的 你昨晚有不在场证据吗?
You better have one! What did you do with the leads?
你最好有! 你把那些合约怎么了?
If you tell me what you did with the leads, we can talk.
如果你告诉我 我们可以慢慢谈
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
If you tell me where the leads are, I won't turn you in.
如果你告诉我合约在哪里 我不会告发你的
If you don't, I'm gonna tell the cop you stole them.
否则我告诉警察是你偷的
Mitch and Murray will see that you go to jail, believe me, they will!
米奇和默里会看见你被关进监狱的!
Now, where are the leads?
告诉我合约在哪里?
I'm walking in that door. You got five seconds
我要进去告诉警察了 你只有五秒钟时间
- or you are going to jail! - Go ahead.
- 否则就要坐牢了! - 你去吧
I don't care, you understand?
我才不在乎 你明白吗?
Where are the leads?
合约在哪里?
All right.
好吧
I sold them.
我把它们卖了
To Jerry Graff.
卖给了谢利格拉夫
How much did you get for them?
你得到多少钱?
你拿到多少钱?
Five. Five grand.
五千块
- I got half. - Who got the other half?
- 我拿到一半 - 那另外一半呢?
Do I have to tell you?
我要告诉你吗?
Moss.
莫斯
Well, that was easy, wasn't it?
钱来的真容易 对吗?
- His idea. - Was it?
- 是他的主意 - 是吗?
I think he got more than five, actually.
我想实际上他拿到不止五千
He told me my cut was 2500.
他告诉我能分到两千五百块
Wait a minute. Okay... hey, hey, John!
等等 嘿 嘿 约翰!
Wait... okay, John! Hey, Johnny.
等等 约翰! 嘿 约翰
Listen. Come here, come here.
过来
Eh, John?
约翰?
Last night...
昨晚...
I gotta tell you, I'm ready to "do the Dutch."
我得告诉你 我都准备自杀了
I'm done. Moss gets me, "Do this, we'll get well."
莫斯救了我 "做了这事大家都有好处"
Why not? Big fucking deal. I'm halfway hoping to get caught.
为什么不做呢?一笔大买卖 我希望我被抓住
Hey... put me out of my misery. It taught me something, John.
解决我的痛苦吧 我学到了很多东西 约翰
What it taught me... you gotta get out there!
这教晓了我 要那样做才行!
I'm not cut out to be a thief, I'm cut out to be a salesman.
我该是做经纪 而不是小偷!
And I am back. I got my balls back.
现在我重新找回了自信
Now... you got a slight advantage on me.
现在 你抓住我的弱点了
But whatever it takes, John,
但无论要什么代价 约翰
to make things right, we're gonna make it right.
我都要弄妥这事情
We are going to make it right.
我们会弄妥这事情的
I want to tell you something, Shelly.
我要告诉你件事 沙利
- Eh? - You have a big mouth.
- 什么? - 你的嘴巴不牢靠
What?
什么?
You've got a big mouth!
你的嘴巴不牢靠!
And now I'm gonna show you an even bigger one.
现在我让你看看更大的嘴巴
Where are you going?
你要去哪里?
You can't do that! You don't want to do that.
你不能那么做! 你不想那么做的
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
等等
It's $2,500. Go ahead and take it, take it all.
这里是两千五百块 全都拿去吧
No, I don't think so. I don't think I want your money.
我不想要你的臭钱
I think you fucked up my office, and I think you're going away.
你在我的地盘生事 你得离开这里!
Are you nuts? I'm gonna close for you! Take...
你疯了吗? 我会替你赚钱!
I'm gonna make this office and be number one on that board again.
我会重新爬到销售榜首的
Wait, John.
等等 约翰
John... okay.
约翰...好吧
This is what we're gonna do... 20%.
我给你我销售额的20%
I'm gonna give you 20% of all my sales.
我做的每单生意都给你20%
20%, as long as I'm with this firm.
只要我在这里干下去
50%
- 50% of all my sales. - What sales?
- 我销售额的一半 - 什么生意?
What sales? My God, I just closed 82 grand.
我刚做了八万两千块的生意
Are you out of your fucking mind? I'm back! This is just the beginning!
你疯了吗? 我又重振雄风了!这只是开始!
Just the beginning? Where have you been, Shelly?
只是刚开始? 你去过哪里 沙利?
Bruce and Harriett Nyborg... do you want to see the memos?
布鲁斯和哈瑞特那里... 你要看备忘录吗?
They're nuts. They used to call in every week...
他们是疯子 他们曾每星期都打电话来
when I was with Webb... we were selling Arizona.
那时我还和韦伯在一起 我们在卖亚里桑那的地产
They're nuts.
他们是疯子
Did you see how they were living? How can you delude yourself?
你有看到他们是怎么生活的? 你怎能自欺欺人?
- I've got their check. - Forget it. Frame it.
- 我拿到了他们的支票 - 算了吧
- It's worthless. - The check is no good?
- 一文不值的 - 支票是无效的?
You want to stick around? I'll pull the memo. I'm busy.
你要看备忘录吗 上面写的很清楚 我很忙
The check is no good? They're nuts?
支票是无效的? 他们是疯子?
You want to call the bank? I called them.
你要去问银行吗?我找过了
I called them four months ago when we first got the lead.
四个月前完成第一笔生意时 我就找过银行了
The people are insane.
他们有神经病
They just like talking to salesmen.
他们只是喜欢和经纪聊天
- Don't! - I'm sorry.
- 别那样! - 我很抱歉
- Why? - Because I don't like you.
- 为什么? - 因为我不喜欢你
My daughter.
我女儿
Fuck you.
去你的
Asshole.
混蛋
Guy couldn't find his fucking couch in the living room.
有人在客厅里找不到躺椅
What a day.
今天真好
I haven't even had a cup of coffee.
我连咖啡也没喝过
Jag-off John opens his mouth, blows my Cadillac.
约翰乱说话害我不见了卡迪拉克
I swear, it's not a world of men.
我敢发誓这不是人类世界
It is not a world of men, "Machine."
不是人类的世界 "机器"
It's a world of clock-watchers...
这世界到处都是混时间的人
bureaucrats...
官僚主义者
officeholders, what it is.
官员 这些是什么
It's a fucked-up world.
这是个他妈的世界
No adventure to it.
毫无新意
Dying breed. Yes, it is.
死气沉沉 对
We're the members of a dying breed. That's... that's...
我们是垂死的生物 所以
that's why we got to stick together. Shel?
所以我们才会聚在一起 沙利?
I want to talk to you.
我想和你谈谈
I've wanted to talk to you for some time...
我早就想和你谈谈了
for a long time, actually. I said, "The Machine"...
一早就想和你谈了 我说 "机器"...
there's a man I would work with.
这才是我会和他合作的人
There's..." you know, I never said a word.
你知道 我从不称赞别人
I don't know why I didn't. I should've, I don't know why.
我不知道为什么
And that shit you were slinging on my guy today...
你刚才教训他的那些话
that was so good. That... it...
真是说的太好了
excuse me for saying this, it's not even my place to say it.
对不起 我根本没权那样说
That was admirable.
令人敬佩
It was the old stuff.
是古老的那套
Hey, I've been on a hot streak.
我性情急燥
So what? Things I can learn from you.
我能向你学些东西
- You eat today? - Me?
- 你吃了饭没有? - 我?
Yeah.
对
Want to swing around the Chinks'... watch me eat, we'll talk?
一起去查克斯 边吃边谈好吗?
I think I'll stay around awhile.
我想我得多留一会儿
Hello, Mrs. Schwartz?
史太太吗?
This is Richard Roma with Premiere Properties.
我是第一地产的理查德诺马
You or your accountant requested information on a land investment
你的你的会计询问过
which would offer you depreciation and the chance
有关小本大利的地产投资
of a substantial return on a small investment.
这件事有眉目了
I'm in from Florida just for one day...
我刚从佛罗里达过来 只能待一天
- Mr. Levene? - ...so I only have that one lot left.
- 赖芬先生? - 我只剩下一个单位了
Would you come in here, please?
请你进来一下好吗?
I don't have too much time and I'm on the midnight plane back,
我时间不多要乘夜机回去
so if you or your husband are truly interested...
如果你或你丈夫真的感兴趣的话
because I can't hold this parcel past...
因为我不能一直留起它
Yes?
是
Well, what would be better for you... say, 6:00 or 8:00?
那你几点比较方便? 六点还是八点?
Go ask him. Shel... we're gonna talk? I'm going to the Chinks'.
去问他沙利...我们找时间谈谈? 我会去查克斯
When you're done, come down. We're gonna smoke a cigarette.
你和他谈完了就来找我 我们一起抽烟
- I... - Get in the room.
- 我... - 快进去
Hey. Hey, easy, pal. That's "The Machine."
嘿 放松点 朋友 他是"机器"
This is Shelly "The Machine" Levene.
这是沙利赖芬 "机器"
- Get in the goddamn room. - Rick, I...
- 快进去 - 理查德 我...
- I'll meet you at the restaurant. - Ricky...
- 餐厅见 - 理查德...
- Ricky can't help you. - All I want is...
- 理查德帮不了你 - 我只是想...
What do you want? You want to what?
你想怎样?
- Rick? Rick? - Hello? Excellent.
- 理查德? - 喂? 好极了
8:00 p.m. 6947 Euclid.
晚上八点 6947 欧几里得
Not at all... thank you very much.
别客气 谢谢你
They find the guy that broke in the office?
他们找到了那窃贼?
No. I don't know.
不 我不知道
Did the leads come in yet?
生意来了没有?
No.
还没有
Oh God, I hate this job.
天啊 我讨厌这份工作
Anybody wants me, I'm at the restaurant.
有人找我的话就说我在餐厅
Hello, Mrs. Delgari?
喂?杜佳太太?
Yes... you requested some information about Rio Rancho Properties?
你询问过有关尼奥牧场的地产?
☆ Blue skies smiling at me ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies do I see ☆
☆ In the morning there's bluebirds ☆
☆ Singing a song ☆
☆ Nothing but bluebirds ☆
☆ From now on ☆
☆ I never saw the sun shining so bright ☆
☆ Never saw things going so right ☆
☆ Noticing the days hurrying by ☆
☆ When you're in love, my, how they fly ☆
☆ Blue days, all of them gone ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies from now on... ☆
☆ Blue skies smiling at me ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies do I see ☆
☆ In the morning there's bluebirds ☆
☆ Singing a song ☆
☆ Nothing but, nothing but bluebirds from now on ☆
☆ Let me tell you I never saw the sun ☆
☆ Shining so bright ☆
☆ Never saw things going so right ☆
☆ Noticing the days hurrying by ☆
☆ When you're in love, my, how they fly ☆
☆ Blue skies smiling at me ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies do I see ☆
☆ In the morning there's bluebirds ☆
☆ Singing a song ☆
☆ Nothing but, nothing but bluebirds from now on ☆
☆ Let me tell you I never saw the sun ☆
☆ Shining so bright ☆
☆ Never saw things going so right ☆
☆ Noticing the days hurrying by ☆
☆ When you're in love, my how they fly ☆
☆ Blue days ☆
☆ All of them, all of them gone ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies from now on ☆
☆ Now on ☆
☆ Nothing but blue skies. ☆